<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Grand concern of England explained in several proposals offered to the consideration of the Parliament, (1) for payment of publick debts, (2) for advancement and encouragement of trade, (3) for raising the rents of lands ... / by a lover of his countrey, and well-wisher to the prosperity both of the King and kingdoms.</title>
            <author>Lover of his countrey and well-wisher to the prosperity both of the king and kingdoms.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1673</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 171 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 33 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A41753</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing G1491</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R23421</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12068670</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12068670</idno>
            <idno type="VID">53444</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A41753)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 53444)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 71:13)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Grand concern of England explained in several proposals offered to the consideration of the Parliament, (1) for payment of publick debts, (2) for advancement and encouragement of trade, (3) for raising the rents of lands ... / by a lover of his countrey, and well-wisher to the prosperity both of the King and kingdoms.</title>
                  <author>Lover of his countrey and well-wisher to the prosperity both of the king and kingdoms.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 92 [i.e. 62] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1673.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Page 62 is incorrectly numbered 92.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Yale University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Great Britain --  Economic policy.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Zev Berger</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Zev Berger</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:53444:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:53444:1"/>
            <p>
               <hi>THE Grand Concern Of ENGLAND EXPLAINED;</hi> IN SEVERAL <hi>PROPOSALS Offered to the Conſideration of the</hi> PARLIAMENT.</p>
            <list>
               <item>
                  <hi>1.</hi> For Payment of Publick Debts.</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>2.</hi> For Advancement and Encouragement of Trade.</item>
               <item>
                  <hi>3.</hi> For Raiſing the Rents of Lands.</item>
            </list>
            <p>
               <hi>In Order whereunto, It is proved Neceſſary,</hi>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <hi>I.</hi> That a Stop be put to further Buildings in and about <hi>London.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>II.</hi> That the Gentry be obliged to live ſome part of the Year in the Countrey.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>III.</hi> That Regiſters be ſetled in every County.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>IV.</hi> That an Act for Naturalizing all Foreign Proteſtants; and Indulging them; and His Majeſtie's Subjects at home, in Matters of Conſcience, may be paſſed.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>V.</hi> That the Act Prohibiting the Importation of <hi>Iriſh</hi> Cattel, may be Repealed.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>VI.</hi> That <hi>Brandy, Coffee. Mum; Tea,</hi> and <hi>Chocolata,</hi> may be prohibited.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>VII.</hi> That the Multitude of Stage-Coaches and Caravans may be ſuppreſſed.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>VIII.</hi> That no Leather may be Exported <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>n-manufactured.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>IX.</hi> That a <hi>Court of Conſcience</hi> be ſetled for <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and all the Suburbs of <hi>London,</hi> and in every City and Corporation in <hi>England.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>X.</hi> That the Extravagant Habits and Expence of all Perſons may be curbed; the Exceſſive Wages of Servants and Handicrafts-men may be Reduced, and all Foreign Manufactures may be prohibited.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>XI.</hi> That it may be made lawful to Aſſign Bills, Bonds, and other Securities; and that a Courſe be taken to prevent the Knavery of <hi>Bankrupts.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>XII.</hi> That the <hi>Newcaſtle</hi>-Trade for Coals may be managed by Commiſſioners, to the Eaſe of the Subjects, and great Advantage of the Publick.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>XIII.</hi> That the <hi>Fiſhing-Trade</hi> may be vigorouſly proſecuted, all poor People ſet at work to make <hi>Fiſhing-Tackle,</hi> and be paid out of the Money Collected every Year for the Poor, in the ſeveral Pariſhes in <hi>England.</hi>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>By a Lover of his Countrey, and Well-wiſher to the Proſperity both of the King and Kingdoms.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>London, <hi>Printed in the Year, 1673.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:53444:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:53444:2"/>
            <head>PROPOSALS humbly offered to conſideration of the Parliament, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <list>
               <item>1. <hi>For diſcharging the Publick Debts of the Kingdom.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>2. <hi>For Encouraging and Advancement of Tradc.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>3. <hi>The Increaſe of the Rents of Lands.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <p>THE Honour, Intereſt and Safety of a Kingdom lies in maintaining the Grandure and Dignity of their KING, and the Prerogative of his Crown; The which can no way be better ſecured, than by pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viding him a plentiful Revenue wherewith to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fray the Publick Expences of the Kingdom, encou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rage and help all his Friends and Allies, maintain Forces for his Own, his Subjects, and the Kingdoms Safeguard at home, and a ſufficient Fleet at Sea for the Security of Trade abroad, and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence of his Kingdom againſt all Forreign Princes and Potentates; and wherewith alſo to diſcharge ſuch Publick Debts as are juſtly owing to any perſon upon valuable Conſideration.</p>
            <p>If the payment of Publick Debts were provided for, the reſt would be eaſily ſecured, without any great Charge to the People, and the King be freed from the neceſſity of calling for freſh Supplie every year from his Subjects, which now comes very hard, and makes Parliaments un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eaſie to themſelves as well as to thoſe whoſe Repreſentatives they are.</p>
            <p>The vaſt Debt contracted by his Majeſty when beyond the Seas, the great Summs he hath ſince his happy Reſtauration given to relieve ſome of the many poor (yet Loyal) Subjects, that ſerved him and his Royal Father faithfully, and loſt their Limbs and Eſtates in their Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice; The great Debts he found the Kingdom in to the Army and Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy when he came firſt home, which are all paid off, excepting about 150000 <hi>l.</hi> that hath been under conſideration of the Parliament, which if not paid, will be the ruine of many thouſands of poor Families, who
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:53444:3"/>advanced the ſame for his Majeſties Service, and it was all employed for the bringing him home.</p>
            <p>The great charge of the laſt and this preſent Dutch War, both which his Majeſtie hath been neceſſitated unto, for the preſervation of the dignity of his Perſon, (which they ſo baſely ſcorn'd and contemn'd) the Honour of his Kingdom, and the intereſt and ſecurity of Trade: theſe, together with the Money's expended in the reparations of his Ruined Houſes, repurchaſing his own Goods, and others for furniſhing his Royal Palaces, and many other publick affairs, have called for frequent and great Supplies.</p>
            <p>Which howbeit the Parliament have thought fit freely to grant when the King hath deſired the ſame, and paſſed ſeveral Acts for Pole-money, Benevolence-money, Subſidies, Hearth-money, additional Exciſe, Taxes upon the Law, poundage upon Rents, and Land-Taxes, yet the pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Debts are very great, and the reaſon of it is plainly becauſe whatever hath been given (excepting Land-Taxes) was ſo overvalued in the granting thereof, the Grants ſo uncertain, the Collecting ſo trouble<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſom and chargeable, the Payment ſo vexatious to the People, that the end of the Parliament hath not been anſwered, the King hath not had the Supply intended, nor the Subjects the benefit or eaſe deſigned; but the quite contrary events have hapned.</p>
            <p>So that it's humbly conceived there's nothing can be more for the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt and advantage of the King and Kingdom, than for the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to examine what the publick Debts really are, how contracted, and when; and to ſee where the King has been well or ill uſed, where Perſons have made uſurious or advantageous Contracts, and taken advantage of the King's neceſſities, to impoſe ill Commodities and at unreaſonable rates upon him, and there to reduce the Debt to ſuch a preportion, as the Commodity ſold was (at the time of ſuch Sale) really worth; and to ſee where the King hath been juſtly dealt with; which done, and the Accounts being brought to Balance, and the Debt ſtated and known; then at once to raiſe ſo much Money as may diſcharge the whole, and appoint Perſons to ſee the money ſo to be raiſed, diſpoſed to that and no other uſe; allowing them indif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferent Salaries for their pains, that ſo they may mind the work, and recieve no manner of Fees or advantage from the Creditor, whereby the publick Debts may be leſſened: for whoever hath truſted the King, had a reſpect (in ſetting his price on the Commodities fold) to the time he thought he ſhould ſtay for his Money, the uncertainty of ever receiving it, the vaſt Charge he muſt be at in Exchequer Fees, Gratuities, &amp;c. when
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:53444:3"/>ever he ſhould have obtained the ſame, inſomuch that publiek Debts were and are frequently ſold at ſixty or ſeventy pounds <hi>per cent.</hi> And ſo, what hinders but that if this Buſineſs be prudently mannaged by Perſons to be intruſted for that purpoſe, the publick Debts may be leſſened, and the more eaſily paid? which done, the Subjects may rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonably expect, and hope for the future to be at quiet and freed from the fears they are now under of a Parliaments meeting, leſt ſtill there ſhould be freſh ſupplies for the purpoſes aforeſaid demanded, and given, and no end be known of ſuch Gifts; and yet to his Majeſty and the Kingdoms great diſhonour both at home and abroad, the publick Debts ſtill remain undiſcharged. And if Money for this purpoſe ſhall be by the Parliament thought fit to be given, It is humbly offered and ſubmitted to their conſiderations, whether there can be any way in the World found, more certain, equal, and eaſie, to raiſe the ſame, than by a Land-Tax: for then they will know what it is they give, when and how certainly it will come in, and the time when the ſame will end, and may proportion their Contracts and Payments accordingly. Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides, a Land-Tax will be a certain Fond for to advance Money upon in a ſhort time, at eaſie Intereſt, wherewith ſpeedily to diſcharge and pay off thoſe Debts, for which now great intereſt is to be paid.</p>
            <p>I know it will be Objected, that Land is a Drug, bears little or no Price to be let, or be ſold; what Rent it is let for, Tenents are not able to pay; for to lay Taxes upon that, would utterly undo the Gentry, who have nothing to live upon but their Rents.</p>
            <p>To this I anſwer, that it is very true, Lands let poorly, Rents are ill paid, and yeild very little, if ſold. But let us examine the Reaſons hereof, and ſee if ſome things may not be propoſed to remedy thoſe Miſchiefs, and bring Land to its former value: which if we do, then every Man will certainly be of Opinion that a Land-Tax is the beſt way to raiſe Money, and be glad on that Condition to have it impoſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed.</p>
            <p>I am of Opinion, that Gentlemens being wanting to themſelves, is the greateſt occaſion of the decay of their Eſtates, and lowering of their Rents. Now in Order to the bringing them to the ſame Rate and Value, if not to a better than they formerly bore, I humbly propoſe that theſe ſeveral Particulars following (which can only be done by Act of Parliament) may be enacted as Laws. And I ſhall endeavour to Demonſtrate the Miſcheifs we ſuffer for want of them, and the great Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantages we may rationally expect to receive by their being Enacted.
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:53444:4"/>
               <list>
                  <item>1. I propoſe that a ſtop be put to any farther Buildings in or about the Cities of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> Borough of <hi>Southwark,</hi> or in any place within the Weekly-Bills of Mortality, the Head being already too big for the Body. And that a years Value of all Houſes Built upon New Foundations may by the Owners of ſuch Houſes be paid to the King towards payment of Publick Debts, which would advance above 300000 <hi>l.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>2. That all the Nobility and Gentry of <hi>England</hi> who have Eſtates in the Country, and are not obliged to atterd on His Majeſty by rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of their Offices, be enjoyned with their Families to live where their Eſtates do lie, ſo many Months in each year as to the Wiſdom of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment ſhall ſeem meet.</item>
                  <item>3. That a Bill be paſſed for ſetting up of Regiſters in every County for Regiſtring Sales, Mortgages, Leaſes for term of Years or Lives, and all other real Securities, and if poſſible all Bonds, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which Work may be done with little charge to the Subject, and yet a profit of above 50000 <hi>l. per annum</hi> ariſe to the Publick.</item>
                  <item>4. That an Act for a General Naturalizing of all Foreign Prote<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants be paſſed, and an aſſurance of Liberty of Conſcience given to all that ſhall come over into <hi>England,</hi> and place themſelves and Fami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lies amongſt us. And that the ſame priviledge be given to his Majeſties Subjects at home.</item>
                  <item>5. That the Act for prohibition of the Importation of <hi>Iriſh</hi> Cattle be repealed, and a Trade between the two Kingdoms Eſtabliſhed, whereby his Mejeſties Revenue of Cuſtoms would be advanced above 80000 <hi>l. per annum.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>6. That <hi>Brandy</hi> and <hi>Mum, Coffee</hi> and <hi>Tea</hi> be prohibited, and Cof<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fee-houſes ſuppreſſed, which may be done without any dimunution of his Majeſties Revenue of Exciſe.</item>
                  <item>7. That the multitude of Stage-Coaches and Caravans now travel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling upon the Roads be all or moſt of them ſuppreſſed; eſpecially thoſe within forty or fifty Miles of <hi>London</hi> where they are ino way neceſſary, and yet moſt numerous and miſchievous; and that a due regulation be made of ſuch as ſhall be thought fit to be continued. Which done, his Majeſties Exciſe would be worth above 30000 <hi>l. per annum</hi> more than it now is, and the Poſt-Office by 6000 <hi>l. per annum.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>8. That the Act for Tranſportation of Leather Unmanufactured be repealed, or ſo far diſcountenanced at leaſt, that it be not renewed when the ſeven years is expired.</item>
                  <item>9. That a Court in the nature of the Court of Requeſt in <hi>London</hi>
                     <pb n="5" facs="tcp:53444:4"/>be eſtabliſhed for <hi>Weſtminſter, Southwark,</hi> and all parts within the Week<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly-Bills of Mortality if poſſible, and in every City and Town Corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate in <hi>England,</hi> to determine differences between poor People, for ſmall Debts, Words, or Treſpaſſes, that ſo they may not be undone by Law Suits.</item>
                  <item>10. That a Bound be put to the Extravagant Habits, and Expences of all ſorts of Perſons, that Servants and Handicraft Tradeſmens exceſſive Wages may be reduced, and that no foreign Manufactures, except from <hi>Ireland,</hi> be ſuffered to be worn in <hi>England,</hi> but that the importation and expoſing of them knowingly to Sale be both made Felony.</item>
                  <item>11. That it be made Lawful to aſſign Bills, Bonds and other Securities, And the Frauds of Men Breaking, with deſign to Enrich themſelves out of their Creditors Eſtates may be prevented.</item>
                  <item>12. That the New-Caſtle Trade for Coles may be managed by Commiſſioners for his Majeſty, which would be a great advantage to the Subjects, and raiſe his Majeſty above 300000 <hi>l. per annum.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>13. That the Fiſhing Trade be encouraged, all Poor ſet at Work to provide Tackle for that uſe, and be paid out of the Money Collect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed yearly in every Pariſh throughout <hi>England</hi> for relief of the Poor, which would be of vaſt advantage to the Publick.</item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <p>In Order to the evincing of the neceſſity of Prohibiting any of further Building in and about <hi>London,</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and of the Gentries being confined to live ſome part of the year upon their Eſtates in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, I deſire every ſerious conſiderate Perſon, that knew <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and the Suburbs thereof, fourty or fifty years ago, (when <hi>England</hi> was far richer and more populous than now it is) to tell me whether by Additional Buildings upon new Foundations, the ſaid Cities and Suburbs, ſince that time, are not become at leaſt a third part bigger than they were; and whether in thoſe days they were not thought and found large enough, to give a due reception to all perſons that were fit, or had occaſion to reſort thither (whereupon all further Buildings on new Foundations (even in thoſe dayes) were prohibited? Neverthe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs, above thirty thouſand Houſes great and ſmall have been ſince built, the conſequences whereof may be worthy of our conſideration. Theſe Houſes are all inhabited, conſidering then what multitudes of whole Families, formerly dwelling in and about the ſaid Cities, were cut off by the two laſt dreadful Plagues, as alſo by the War abroad and at home, by Land and by Sea; and how many have tranſported themſelves, (or been tranſported) into our foreign Plantations; and it muſt naturally follow, that thoſe who inhabit theſe new Houſes and many of the old
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:53444:5"/>ones, muſt be perſons coming out of the Country; which makes ſo ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Inhabitants the leſs there, where they are moſt needful and wanting. For, the occaſion of the Rents of Lands falling every year, ariſes not ſo much from Lands growing worſe, as becauſe of the want of Tenants with good Stocks to manage the Farms they take. And this miſchief hath been, and is in great meaſure occaſioned by theſe additional Build<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings; for, had they not been erected, thoſe who inhabit them, would have been in the Country, living an Induſtrious and Laborious Life, improving their Stocks, and thereby advantaging Gentlemens Lands, and the Trade of the Nation. But now, if a Man get two or three Hundred pounds in his Pocket, up he comes to <hi>London,</hi> takes a Houſe, payes a Fine, layes out the reſt of his Money in furniſhing it for Lodgers, thereby promiſing himſelf a lazy Life, free from care; or elſe he ſets up an Alehouſe, or Brandy Houſe, (both tending to the debauching and deſtroying of Youth;) when as had there not been theſe Buildings to draw them hither, and give ſhelter, then thoſe Men with their three or four hundred pounds a piece Stocks employed in the Country, might have made each of them a good Tenant, for a Farme of 100 or 200 <hi>l. per annum;</hi> which Farms by their removing to <hi>London,</hi> are thrown into the Landlords hands ſo that by a moderate Calculation, it is judged, that there are 60000 Families at leaſt now in and about <hi>London,</hi> more than would or could conveniently have been, if theſe Houſes had not been Built; which Families if they had continued in the Country, would have kept up the value of Lands which fall only for want of Tenants: If therefore more Buildings ſhould be hereafter erected; more Miſchiefs in all probability will be done of this kind to the Country; And really, Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen may thank themſelves for the prejudice they receive by theſe means, they having given the example, and been the occaſion thereof. For, they never thinking their Eſtates would have an end, weary of an honeſt and commendable Country-life, come up to <hi>London</hi> to ſee faſhions, fall into ill company, learn how to run out of all their Eſtates in a ſhort time, by extravagant Habits, gaming, drinking, and other debau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cheries, deſtructive to their Healths as much as Eſtates; As if to have lived in the Country upon their own Eſtates and to have taken care of and managed them, and kept a handſome retinue of Servants, and a good Houſe of Hoſpitality, and to have taken off their Tenants Proviſions for their Family expences, in part of their Rents, relieving and ſetting the Poor at work, and incouragement of Art, Induſtry and Labour, were not ſo commendable in them, or ſo much for their Advantage, and Honour, as to live idly in <hi>London,</hi> purſuing their luſtful pleaſures,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:53444:5"/>paying, whileſt their own houſes ſtand empty, and go to ruine for want of being inhabited, more for their Lodgings than would maintain their Families handſomely in the Country, and encreaſe the Conſumption of the Proviſions, and Manufactures of the Kingdom, than which nothing can conduce more to the Improvement of Land. I would deſire to know of any ſober Perſon, how far the many Gentlemen who have thus fooliſhly and idly run themſelves out of their Eſtates, have done good with the ſame? who is the better for it? Is the Country, where their Eſtates lie, or their Tenants that rent them? or the poor Inhabitants about them? No, not at all, but all are the worſe, and undone there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by, for when theſe Perſons come firſt to <hi>London,</hi> they bring up all the Money they can get in <hi>ſpecie,</hi> and no ſooner do their Rents grow due in the Country, but they or their Bailiffs or Stewards rack the poor Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants for the ſame, gather in all that they can get, and ſue, or diſtrain where Money is not preſently to be had, taking away Tenants Cattel, ſelling them for half their worth, and thereby ruine not only idle Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons or ill Husbands that have run out of their Stocks, but alſo many Induſtrious men and great husbands, who have Stock and Goods enough (if ſold) wherewith to anſwer the Rent; and the want of a vent for the product of their Farms is the only reaſon why they could not raiſe pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Money for their Landlords. How many perſons by theſe means have been undone! forced to leave their Farms! which thereby have been thrown into their Owners hands; who have been forced both to abate Rents, and keep their Farms a year or two without making any thing of them, before they could diſpoſe of them again. And I know none the better for theſe things but the Gentries and Nobilities Bailifs and Stewards, who being entruſted to Let and Set, Receive Rents and manage their Maſters Eſtates, do by their neglecting to call them to ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count, or looking after and diſpoſing their own Affairs, grow vaſtly Rich, and frequently in Truſtees names become Purchaſers of their Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters Eſtates; whilſt they in the mean time, by means as aforeſaid, become greatly impoveriſhed. The rather, for that frequently, when they receive their Maſters Rents, they pretend the Tenants have them in their hands, and put their Maſters thereby under neceſſity of borrowing Money for their preſent Supplies; which when they have done, they being imployed to procure the ſame, do frequently furniſh them with their own Money, making them pay Brocage, Procuration and Continuation-Money, and Intereſt for the ſame, which helps forward their Ruine.</p>
            <p>In ſhort, theſe New Buildings are advantageous to none but to the Owners of the Ground on which they are built, who have raiſed their
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:53444:6"/>wonted Rents from a hundred pound to five or ſix hundred pound <hi>per annum,</hi> beſides the Improvements in Reverſion; or to the Builders, who by ſlight building on long Leaſes, make ten or twelve pound <hi>per cent.</hi> of their moneys. But the advantage of theſe perſons being the Countries great prejudice, Therefore in my poor Opinion, it ſeems agreeable to Reaſon that they ought to help to pay the publick Debts of the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom; and the Country (who are hurt by them) ſhould be eaſed: And for them to pay one year, or a year and halfs Improved Rent to the King, would not be much, conſidering the greatneſs of the Improve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment they have and are like to make. So that admitting that there are 30000 Houſes Built upon New Foundations as aforeſaid, and that each of thoſe Houſes (one with another) ſhould pay but 10 <hi>l. per annum</hi> Rent, and the King ſhould have but one years Rent from each Houſe, the ſame would amount unto above 300000 <hi>l.</hi> which would go a great way in the diſcharging the publick Debts; But one years Rent from each of theſe Houſes (it is conceived) would come to above 500000 <hi>l.</hi> and the enforcing them that have Built contrary to the Statute to pay ſuch a Fine, would deter others from Building for the future; of which there can be no need; conſidering that there are above 3000 brave Houſes which, for the Honour of the Nation, are at great charge, to the ruine of the Builders, rebuilt, ſtand empty within <hi>London</hi> Walls, and are like ſo to do, by reaſon that the Trade is drawn out of the City to the new Erected Buildings in the Suburbs, where the Inhabi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants have theſe advantages following.
<list>
                  <item>1. They have Houſes at eaſier rates, becauſe built at leſſer charge than thoſe in the City, which were Built when all Materials were very ſcarce and dear, and Workmens Wages extream high.</item>
                  <item>2. They are certain in moſt places to raiſe their Rents by letting Lodgings, eſpecially near the Inns of Court, <hi>Whitehal</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter;</hi> the Gentry coveting to Lodge thereabouts, and they have not only Lodgings, but the advantage of their Cuſtomer alſo for ſuch Commodi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties as they ſell, and their Lodgers want. Which hinders the Trade of the City, where little or no benefit at all is made by Lodgings.</item>
                  <item>3. They are not liable to a third penny of charges for Taxes and pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Duties that they are who live within the City; whereby they can aford to ſell at a lower rate than in <hi>London</hi> they can do. All which inevitably tends to deſtruction of the Trade within the Walls.</item>
               </list>
            </p>
            <div type="section">
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:53444:6"/>
               <head>III.</head>
               <p>THe Third thing propoſed is, <hi>A Bill of REGISTERS;</hi> That in every County a Regiſter may be ſetled, to Regiſter all Bills of Sale, Judgments, Statutes, Recognizances, Bonds, Mortgages, Leaſes, and Conveyances of Land, than which nothing can be of grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter advantage to Gentlemen, Security to Purchaſers, or benefit to the publick, without hurt to any, unleſs the profeſſors of the Law, or ſuch who intend and deſign to defraud Purchaſers.</p>
               <p>Thoſe therefore that ſhall oppoſe ſo excellent and beneficial an Act as this, muſt be either, firſt, ſuch who live by the practice of the Law; or ſecondly, ſuch as underſtand not their own Intereſt: or thirdly, ſuch as deſign to live by defrauding others. The oppoſition ariſing from the practiſers of the Law is not ſo much from their conviction that the thing in it ſelf is not good, and beneficial to the publick, as from ſelf-Intereſt, which too much governs all ſorts of Men in this Age, Men being apt to prefer private advantage before a general good. I confeſs, a Regiſter may prove a great hinderance to thoſe of that profeſſion: For, in ſhort time it would prevent the multitudes of Suites that yearly ariſe between his Majeſties Subjects occaſioned by the Cheats that are committed for want of ſuch a Regiſtry as is propoſed; and perhaps would ſave the Subjects at leaſt two or three hundred thouſand pounds <hi>per annum</hi> which now is ſpent in thoſe Suites; which if prevented, and the Money ſaved to the People, would be imployed in Trade, or ſpent upon the Manufactures and Proviſions of the Kingdom; and ſo the number of Attourneys would not increaſe as of late they have done, there being at preſent about 6000 of them, beſides Sollicitors, who live ſcattered about the Country: moſt of whom could not ſubſiſt but by making it their whole ſtudy and buſineſs, to promote Suites and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>troverſies, and encourage quarrelſom perſons to being Actions againſt their Neighbours, for ſmall petty Treſpaſſes, or a frivolous haſty paſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>onate Word or two; thoſe perſons of that employment taking advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage thereby, of inriching themſelves, by impoveriſhing the Subjects: whereas w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> it not for them, ſuch differences might happily be com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſed in a friendly and amicable way.</p>
               <p>The ſecond ſort that I preſume may oppoſe this Act are, Men not ſenſible of their own Intereſt and advantage, nor of that of the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick;
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:53444:7"/>for, if a Regiſter were kept of all Sales, Leaſes for Years, or Lives, Mortgages, Judgments, Statutes, Recognizances, and of all other real Securities, that will or can lay hold on Lands, ſo that in eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry County where any Gentlemans Eſtate lieth, a Man may know by the Regiſter, what Eſtate he hath in that County, and what incumbrances are upon it: therefore if it were declared by Law, that no Incumbrance ſhall be good, but ſuch as if made or entred into before the Act for ſet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tling Regiſters be paſſed, ſhall be regiſtred within one year after the paſſing thereof; or if made or entered into after the paſſing the ſaid Act, ſhall be regiſtred within one month or two after ſuch Conveyan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, or Securities, are entred into or made, or otherwiſe be void, it would highly be for the advantage of all Gentlemen, that either have or may have Land to ſell, or would borrow Money upon Mortgages. For, then they ſhall not need to be beholden unto thoſe Men, that make it their Trades to diſpoſe of Gentlemens Money, to help Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men to Purchaſers for their Lands, or to take up money upon Securi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties; whom now they are forced to make uſe of, and pay great ſums for Brokerage, Procuration, and Continuation-Money. Whereupon I deſire every Gentleman to conſider, when he comes to <hi>London,</hi> and wants Money, how difficult a thing he finds it to ſupply himſelf there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>with, (though he offer good Land-Security.) What begging, intreating, running from place to place? What expences is he put unto? And when all is done, let him conſider whether he can be accommodated without City-Security, (which runs him into further obligations and expences to procure;) and if he does get ſuch, whether he be evertheleſs conſtrained to pay 3, 4, or 5 <hi>l. per cent.</hi> for procuring and ſometimes <hi>viis &amp; modis</hi> 10 <hi>l. per cent.</hi> for what he borrows; And then, it being lent but for a year, the Procurers thereof and their Emiſſaries being wont to contrive which way to make their further advantage of the Borrowers, do commonly at the nine months end ſend them word, that the Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons whoſe Money they borrowed, have great occaſions for the ſame and are forced to call it in, and muſt have it when due; but withall they uſually adviſe them not to be troubled, or take any care; for if they cannot raiſe the Money themſelves, they will furniſh them elſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>where, having the like conſideration for their pains as before; the which theſe Gentlemen are forced to agree unto, becauſe perhaps they know not elſewhere to have it: And when they have thu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> done, then they go to the Perſons, whoſe Money they had lent to theſe Gentlemen the year before, and tell them, that the Gentlemen that borowed the ſame, deſire to pay it in when it ſhall be due; who finding and believing
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:53444:7"/>their ſecurity good, are loth to receive it, never having given any direction to call it in, nor knowing how better to diſpoſe thereof when they receive the ſame; whereupon to pleaſe them alſo, they in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form them that other good ſecurity is ready for them, ſo that the Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney ſhall not lie dead; and ſo they get the advantage of the Gentlemen that had the Money, by procuring other ſums for them, in lieu there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, and of the perſons to whom they lend the Money ſo called in; Inſomuch that by frequent ſhifting the Loan-money from one hand to another, they ſometimes receive to themſelves from the perſons borrow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, as much as the principal Sum lent amounted unto, for Procuration, Brokage and Continuation: whereby the Borrowers at laſt are brought to ſell their Eſtates; and being reduced to ſuch neceſſities by the Subtil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties of theſe perſons, are forced to be beholden to them to procure pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſers: which when they perceive, they uſually play their game as fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>loweth: the ſeller is by them perſwaded that they can get no pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſer, but ſuch as doth object againſt their Title; or their perſons, uſing many frivolous delayes, till they drive them to ſuch diſtreſs, that they muſt ſell at any rate: And then their living remote in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try, or being under protections as Parliament-Men or Courtiers; or their Eſtates lying far from <hi>London,</hi> or the uncertainty of what Incum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>brances may be thereupon, are Objections which they raiſe, pretend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing that all Men they propoſe their Eſtates unto (upon theſe or ſuch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like accounts) are afraid to deal with them, unleſs ſuch as wait for good bargains, and will not purchaſe except they can buy below the Market-price. By which means they ſo contrive the matter with the Venders, that they enforce them to ſell that for thirteen, fourteen or fifteen years purchaſe, which really is worth twenty; And out of that Contract, their manner is to bargain for a good Gratuity for themſelves; although they at the ſame time have agreed with the Purchaſer that is to have the Land, for one or two years purchaſe more than they are to pay to the Sellers. And the better to manage their Deſigns, the Buyers are conceal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and the Land-Brokers and Jobbers of Land find other perſons to perſonate the Purchaſer, ſo that the Vender is never ſuffered to know or ſee them till the Writings be drawn; wherein the Conſiderations are frequently expreſt to be a year or two's Purchaſe more than the Ven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der is to receive for the ſame. Which when they queſtion the Reaſon of, they are informed that it is done, only to enable the Purchaſers to demand better prices when they ſell the ſame, and to keep up the reputed value thereof. Thus do they enrich themſelves by impoſing upon Gentle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men in extremity, through an artificial debaſing the value of their Eſtates,
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:53444:8"/>exacting great Gratuities from the Purchaſers alſo. This is the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Practice of your Land-Brokers and Jobbers and their Confede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rates: But if Regiſters were ſetled, and all Incumbrances regiſtred, ſo that men might be ſecure, no dormant Securities, after they have lent their Money upon Mortgages, or purchaſed for valuable Conſiderations, could be ſtarted up to defeat them of their Intereſts; and then Gentlemen that have Money lying dead by them, would be as glad to lend it; at eaſie rates, to honeſt Gentlemen upon good Security, as thoſe that want it would be to be ſupplied therewith; And Lands undoubtedly would come to be worth, as formerly, twenty years purchaſe, if Men could but be ſecured in their Titles. So that all perſons that either have, or ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe they ever may have any Eſtate to ſell, or Money to borrow, under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand not their own Intereſt, if they oppoſe the ſetling of the Regiſters propoſed.</p>
               <p>The laſt ſort of people that I preſume may be agriev'd at this Regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtry, are ſuch who having lived high, and ſpent their Eſtates extrava<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gantly, and perhaps entred into Judgments, Statutes, and Recognizan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, to double the value thereof, and have mortgaged their Lands over and over, and then get Protections whereby they keep off Suits, or abſcond themſelves ſo that they cannot be found by their Creditors, and are wont thereby to keep their Eſtates in poſſeſſion, and can no way for the future live but by doing further acts of diſhoneſty; which whilſt their Eſtates remain in their poſſeſſion, they have opportunity to do. Such unrighteous Actions will for the future be prevented, and the preſent Deſigns of this nature be defeated, if Regiſters be ſetled. So that ſuch perſons are concerned to oppoſe the ſame. But I hope ſuch Creatures as theſe are, and their Deſigns, will eaſily be ſeen through, and have little reſpect given them by Parliament.</p>
               <p>In ſhort, Were the Regiſtry as deſired, ſetled, and the Profit ariſing thereby brought into the Exchequer, the Work may be done, good Al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowances appointed for thoſe that ſhall be imployed therein, and but a ſmall ſum would be impoſed upon the Subjects for Regiſtring their Claim, and yet by computation at leaſt 50000 <hi>l. per annum</hi> be brought into the Treaſury: which would be an additional help towards pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the Publick Debts.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:53444:8"/>
               <head>IV.</head>
               <p>THe Fourth Thing Propoſed is, That an Act be paſſed for a gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Naturalization of all Foreign Proteſtants, and for granting Liberty of Conſcience to ſuch of them as ſhall come over and Inhabit amongſt us, and that the like Liberty be given to his Majeſties Subjects at home. There is nothing ſo much wanting in <hi>England</hi> as People; and of all ſorts of People, the Induſtrious and Laborious ſort, and Handycraft-men, are wanted to Till and Improve our Land; and help to Manufacture the Staple-Commodities of the Kingdom; which would add greatly to the Riches thereof.</p>
               <p>The two laſt great Plagues, the Civil Wars at Home, and the ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Wars with <hi>Holland, Spain,</hi> and <hi>France,</hi> have deſtroyed ſeveral hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred thouſands of Men, which lived amongſt us; beſides, vaſt num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers have Tranſported themſelves, or been Tranſported into <hi>Ireland,</hi> and other our Foreign Plantations; who, when they were living a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt us, did Eat our Proviſions, Wore off our Manufacturies; im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed themſelves in ſome Calling or other beneficial to the Nation; the want of which calls for a ſupply of People from ſome place or other; and it is, in my judgment, worthy our Obſervation, That the Men thus loſt from amongſt us, are of greater conſideration, and the loſs more miſchievous to the Kingdom, than meerly the death or removal of ſo many Perſons, conſidering that they were Men in the prime of their years, in perfect ſtrength, ſuch, who had they not dyed, or been killed, or removed, might every year have begotten Children, and thereby en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſed the World; So that three times the number of Children might have been better ſpared than they. For inſtance, Say there be but 100000 Men, by theſe means, gone from amongſt us; and inſtead of them 300000 Children had been taken away, and the Men left, it would have been much better; for they in two years and a half, or three years time, might have gotten ſo many Children again; but the Men dying, or being gone, and the Children living, it may be ten or twenty years before they come to Marry and beget Children: And notwithſtanding the great miſchief this Nation hath ſuſtained by the loſs of theſe Men, yet ſo inconſiderate are the Inhabitants thereof, concerning their own Intereſt, (which, if poſſible, is to have the Kingdom full of People) that they are taking up another way to prevent the peopling thereof
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:53444:9"/>for the future, there being almoſt all over <hi>England</hi> a Spirit of Madneſs running abroad, and poſſeſſing Men againſt Marrying, rather chuſing to have Miſtreſſes, by whom very few ever have any Children: And many Marryed Women, by their lewd Converſations, prevent the bringing forth many Children, which otherwiſe they might have had. Theſe Humours and Practices, if continued, will prove ſo miſchievous, that unleſs Foreigners come in amongſt us, in few years there will not be People to Manure our Lands, Eat our Proviſions, Wear our Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factures, or Manufacture the Staple-Commodities that are of the growth of the Kingdom; without which, it is no wonder if Lands yield little Rent, or Sell not for above 14 or 15 years Purchaſe.</p>
               <p>And if Foreigners muſt come over, or our Eſtates here grow worſe, there muſt then Encouragement be given them ſo to do; elſe they will think themſelves Well-Seated where they are, following their Trades, encreaſing their Eſtates, Enjoying all the Liberties and Priviledges of Free-born Subjects, know how (and have Liberty and Encouragement) to improve their Eſtates; and when they have got them can keep them; therefore will never come themſelves, nor bring over their Families or Eſtates amongſt us here to be accounted of as Aliens and Strangers, ſuch as may not purchaſe Eſtates amongſt us; and if they do, ſhall not enjoy the ſame, nor their Children after them. That ſort of people which we moſt want are ſuch, who though they would come over, and dwell a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt us, yet cannot ſpare 50 or 60 <hi>l.</hi> out of their Stock to procure themſelves naturalized by Act of Parliament; eſpecially if they bring over Wife and Children with them (which would be more advantageous for us than for them to come over alone) Or if they ſhould ſpare Money to Naturalize themſelves; yet perhaps they may not have ſo much as to pay for the naturalizing of their Wives and Children; who, as our laws are, cannot be permitted to Inherit, what their Fathers purchaſe, unleſs they be naturalized alſo. So that an Act for a General Natura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lization is abſolutely neceſſary, if we will be ſupplyed with People from Foreign parts; But the paſſing ſuch Act alone, will not be ſuffici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent to encourage Foreigners to come and dwell amongſt us; there muſt be Liberty of Conſcience alſo granted unto them; and they muſt be aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſured that they ſhall not be Impriſoned, Baniſhed, or have their Eſtates ſeized, and taken from them, and ſold, only for differing from the Church of <hi>England,</hi> in the way of their Diſcipline, whilſt they agree in the Fundamentals of Religion, live peaceably under the Civil Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and diſturbe not the Government of the Church eſtabliſhed: for they having ſuch liberty abroad where they are, will not without aſſure<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:53444:9"/>of the ſame here, be induced to come amongſt us; How many thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſands have left <hi>England,</hi> and gone to ſeek ſhelter in Forreign parts, for the perſecution they were under for their Conſciences, who otherwiſe, with their Families, would have Continued amongſt us? How many have been forced to leave their Trades, by being kept in Priſon, and having their Goods and Eſtates taken from them? How many, for fear of being undone, not knowing but that ſo ſoon as their Goods come into their Shops, they may be ſeized for their having been at Conventicles, have left their Trades, drawn off their Stocks, and keep up their Money (not knowing how ſoon they may have occaſion to make uſe of it in the time of their diſtreſſes) which otherwiſe would have been imployed in Trade to the benefit of the Kingdom; How many thouſands of Farmers have been neceſſitated to leave their Farms, and come to dwell in Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don? or to live obſcurely in the Country, for fear leſt when they ſhould have imployed their Stocks, Plowed and Sowed their Land, Reaped their Corn, and Stocked their Paſture-Land, all ſhould be taken from them, and they impriſoned, and forced from their Families, for their Religion? Are not theſe great miſchiefs to the Kingdom, and great reaſons of the decay of Trade, and of Gentlemen their wanting Tenants for their Lands, (a thing ſo generally complained of all over <hi>England</hi>) that men are not ſuffered to live as they would do quietly, and employ and improve their Stocks, as they might do, to the advantage of Trade, and the Kingdom in General; which if they were permitted, would occaſion the Conſumption of more of the proviſions, and Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factures of the Kingdom, Imploy more poor people at Work, and thereby Improve the Rent of Lands, and would ſend many of the Gentry, and Farmers who left the Country for the Reaſons aforeſaid and now live obſcure in London and ſome other places, back to their Country-houſes or to their Farms again; it would remove their Fears, quiet their Minds, and cauſe their Purſes again to be opened, and every one would be putting himſelf upon ſome way of Improving his Eſtate, and not live upon the main Stock, as now they are forced to do. It were greatly to be wiſhed, that there were more love and Charity amongſt us; And that all men would Conſider ſeriouſly what they do, when they take upon themſelves thus to impoſe their own Principles upon all others, as ſuch that are only right, and Condemn all others as Erroneous; this is to magnifie themſelves as Infallible, and deſpiſe all others.</p>
               <p>Upon all theſe Reaſons I humbly ſubmit to Judgment, whether an Act for a general Naturalization, and Liberty of Conſcience, be not abſolute<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly neceſſary at this time? And whether the Paſſing thereof may not be of great advantage to the Kingdom, ſince it would increaſe Trade,
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:53444:10"/>Promote a vaſt Conſumption of the Manufactures and Proviſions of the Kingdom; make us more Induſtrious, Imploy more of our Poor, In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſe his Majeſties Revenue of Cuſtoms, and bring our Lands to let for greater Rents, and to ſell for more years Purchaſe than ever hereto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore they would have done.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <head>V.</head>
               <p>THe Fifth Thing Propoſed is, That the Act for Prohibition of the Importation of Foreign Cattle, ſo far as it relates to <hi>Ireland,</hi> and <hi>Weſtphalia</hi>-Hams, may be Repealed.</p>
               <p>This Act hath no way anſwered the end deſigned by the paſſing there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, but on the contrary proved,</p>
               <list>
                  <item>Firſt, Very prejudicial to his Majeſty in his Revenue of Cuſtoms.</item>
                  <item>Secondly, To all or moſt of the Land-Owners in <hi>England.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>Thirdly, To the Navigation and Trade of the Kingdoms.</item>
               </list>
               <p n="1">1. To his Majeſty: for, before this Act paſſed, there were ſo many great Cattle and Sheep, Imported from <hi>Ireland,</hi> as (Computing the Cuſtom paid for them and for the other Commodities exported out of <hi>England</hi> into <hi>Ireland</hi> in lieu of them) amounted yearly to 80000 <hi>l.</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides the Cuſtoms of all <hi>Norway, Spaniſh,</hi> and <hi>Weſtphalia</hi> Hams; which ſum the King loſeth every year, and the Kingdom, to their Vaſt pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judice, have loſt that Trade.</p>
               <p n="2">2. To Land-Owners this prohibition muſt neceſſarily be a great pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judice, If it be conſidered,
<list>
                     <item>1. That the Breeding-Lands of <hi>England</hi> are not able to raiſe a ſuffici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent Stock for the feeding, ſix months feeding being as much as four years Breeding.</item>
                     <item>2. That by reaſon of the ſcarcity of ſuch Stock, the Breeders Impoſe a greater price on Lean Cattle then they will yield when fatted, whereby Feeding-Land becomes worth little or nothing.</item>
                     <item>3. That for want of <hi>Iriſh</hi> Cattle, the Victualling both for Home-Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumption, and Foreign Trade, and Naval Proviſions, (moſt of it) is tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferred from <hi>England</hi> into <hi>Ireland:</hi> which is a great prejudice to the Conſumption in <hi>England;</hi> So that Lean Cattle, though they be dearer, becauſe of the ſcarcity of them, yet fatted Cattel are cheaper for want of the Conſumption we formerly had. The Conſequence whereof is, That the Ends of the prohibition are not anſwered, Rents of Lands are
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:53444:10"/>not Raiſed; but on the Contrary, Feeding-Lands muſt and do fall for want of a Cheap Stock; and our former Conſumption, and Breeding-Lands, through the decay of Trade, which this prohibition hath occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioned.</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p n="3">3ly, This Prohibition is prejudicial to Trade and Navigation.</p>
               <list>
                  <item>1. Becauſe thoſe Foreigners, who formerly Victualled here, do Victu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>all themſelves in <hi>Ireland.</hi>
                  </item>
                  <item>2. And they have their Proviſions for the fourth part of what we pay for ours; whereby they have a great advantage in point of Trade, and can Sayl Cheaper than we: which forceth the <hi>Engliſh</hi> to Victual there alſo.</item>
                  <item>3. All <hi>Iriſh</hi> Cattle which formerly came unto <hi>England,</hi> and for which they carryed out no Money, but took of our Manufactures in return, are carryed to other places beyond Seas, and from thence fetch the Commodities wherewith we before the prohibition ſupplyed them. So that the Traders in <hi>Lancaſhire, Cheſhire,</hi> and other Northen parts, where the Breeding-Lands lie, their Loſs is greater for want of a Conſumption of the Manufactures of thoſe Countries which formerly were ſent into <hi>Ireland,</hi> than the Advantage they receive by advanceing the price of Lean-cattel doth amount unto.</item>
                  <item>4. It hath enforced the Iriſh for to leſſen their Heards of Cattel, and increaſe their breed of Sheep, having gotten of our largeſt and beſt Breed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers: So that they have now Vaſt Flocks, and prodigious quantities of Wooll, beſides Hides and Tallow: which proves miſcheivous to <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> three wayes.
<list>
                        <item>1. By their ſending Wooll beyond Seas unmanufactured; which not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding the Prohibition, every day they do, which being manufa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctured by Foreigners, they grow rich thereby, whilſt our poor in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> ſtarve for want of the work they had when they were Imployed in manufacturing for a Foreign Conſumption.</item>
                        <item>2. By ſending their Hides, Tallow, and Wooll in great quantities into <hi>England:</hi> which, for want of a Conſumption here, bring down the price of our own growth.</item>
                        <item>3. By ſetting up the Woollen Manufacturies in <hi>Ireland,</hi> where having the Wooll, Land, and all Proviſions cheaper than in <hi>England,</hi> they muſt neceſſarily have their Workmen cheaper; and if ſo, they will be able to make enough, not only for their own uſe, but, to ſupply Foreign<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers alſo with that which <hi>England</hi> uſed to ſupply them with heretofore; which, in a ſhort time, if not prevented, will undermine the Staple and moſt Advantagious Trade of this Kingdom. It is the Intereſt of
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:53444:11"/>
                           <hi>England,</hi> being the Seat of Government, to maintain a preeminence in the Trade, and to ſee that the Manufacturies thereof be preſerved in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tire within it ſelf: Otherwiſe by how much the more <hi>Ireland</hi> is Impro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved, by ſo much the more <hi>England</hi> will be Impaired therein. For they, working cheaper, lying nearer Foreign Markets, and their freight being leſs, do what we can, will underfell us, where ever they come; where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by our Manufacturies will be deſtroyed, and Manufacturers, with their Families, be Ruined.</item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
               <p>It is obſervable, 1. That the Trade with <hi>Ireland</hi> kept three or four hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred ſhips in full imploy; which were paid by the <hi>Iriſh</hi> Freighters there and occaſioned the breeding many Seamen yearly; but now all thoſe ſhips are laid aſide, the breed of Scamen neglected, and that Trade ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>naged in Foreign Bottomes.</p>
               <p n="2">2. That the Cattel and Sheep formerly imported, by Computation amounted unto a Million of Money <hi>per Annum.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="3">3. That they carryed no Money out of <hi>England;</hi> but the effect of their Cattel was all laid out in our Manufacturies, or other Commodities Imported into <hi>England,</hi> and from thence ſent to <hi>Ireland:</hi> and the King had a Cuſtom paid both upon the Importation and Exportation, and alſo for every head of Cattle brought over.</p>
               <p>The <hi>Iriſh</hi> being now Prohibited this Trade, are neceſſitated to ſend all their Victuals to Forreign parts, where they ſell them for more than we paid for them, and buy what ever they want Cheaper than they had them from us; by which means they will be concerned to take no Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities from <hi>England.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Nor can they Trade with us, if they would, becauſe they have no way to pay for what they buy, unleſs they bring over Money <hi>in Specie,</hi> to the miſcheife of that Kingdom; or by Bills of Fxchange, which cannot be had under 15 or 16 <hi>per Cens.</hi> which is double the profit gotten by thoſe that Trade with them. That Exchange of monies thence is very high, Gentlemen whoſe Eſtates are Returned over, do find, and by reaſon there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of are forced to retrench a fixth part of their Expences here: which is a further leſſening to the Conſumption of the Manufacturies &amp; Proviſions of this Kingdom, and of Trade with them: which is further dangerous; for, if we ſend Goods, they having a new Trade to Forreign parts, we muſt ſend our Stocks thither; So that if any loſs happen, it is the <hi>Engliſh</hi> that undergoe it.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Irelands</hi> being peopled from <hi>England</hi> was at firſt a hurt to us, becauſe it leſſened the Conſumption of our Proviſions here. But to prohibit them Trade with us is ten times worſe: for, that not only takes off the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumption
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:53444:11"/>they uſed to make of our Manufactures, but deſtroyes all thoſe Families in <hi>England</hi> that uſed to be Imployed for their ſupply: So that they can neither ſpend of the Proviſions nor Manufacturies of this King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom as formerly they did.</p>
               <p>And beſides theſe Handicraft-men, there are many Eminent Trades in <hi>London,</hi> as Mercers, Milliners, Haberdaſhers, &amp;c, ſuffer greatly: for, when Faſhions were out here, they uſed to ſend them into <hi>Ireland</hi> in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn for their Cattle, and they went off as new there: for want of which utterance, many of thoſe Tradeſmen, by reaſon of the often changing of Faſhions amongſt us, have been, and are daily undone.</p>
               <p>There is one other high Inconveniency like to fall upon <hi>England</hi> by this Prohibition, which hath put <hi>Ireland</hi> upon Induſtry: For ſome part of <hi>Ireland</hi> lying nearer to <hi>France, Italy,</hi> and <hi>Spain</hi> than <hi>England</hi> doth; and ſo the <hi>Iriſh</hi> having Salt from <hi>France,</hi> and Cask, and Mens Labour, and all Tackle for Fiſhing being cheaper there than we have here, do ſet up the Fiſhing Trade there, from whence they need but one Wind to carry them to their Markets; and they catch the Fiſh ſix weeks be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore they come into <hi>England.</hi> If ſo, then what hinders but that they may cure them, and ſupply Foreign Markets ſooner and cheaper than we can? which in time will deſtroy the Fiſheries of this Kingdom.</p>
               <p>Not but that <hi>Ireland</hi> ſhould have its proper Advantages, and may, if they pleaſe; there being many additional Manufactures that both they and we want, to which the nature of that Soyl, and the inclination of the People, gives encouragement; particularly that of Linnen, the greateſt part of the Countrey being Turf-Land, and naturally proper for Hemp and Flax; and being employed to that uſe, (with due regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lations) thoſe Commodities may be had cheaper there, and from thence, than from any other part of the World; which would be a great en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>couragement to the ſetting up of the Manufactures thereof. It muſt neceſſarily be cheaper, becauſe Land is far cheaper there, than in thoſe Parts from whence we have our Hemp and Flax: and what we fetch, comes charged with great Freight and Cuſtoms: Which might be ſaved if the Commodity were fetcht from <hi>Ireland.</hi> What then would there be wanting, but a method to manufacture this Commodity cheaper? Which done, that place may ſupply, not only <hi>England,</hi> but all <hi>Europe</hi> with Linnen-Cloth, at eaſier rates than now they pay for the ſame. And if ſo, what hinders but that they may ingroſs the whole Linnen-Trade, and quickly grow rich? And that they may manufacture cheaper there, conſider, that in this part of the World there cannot be found a place where people may live cheaper, have Lands at eaſier Rates than
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:53444:12"/>in <hi>Ireland;</hi> ſo then conſequently, no place in the World where people work for leſs than there. If then the Commodity to be wrought, and the working of that Commodity be cheaper in <hi>Ireland</hi> than in any other Part, the Manufacturies, when wrought, may be ſold from thence cheaper than from any other part; and this would bring Trade thither, take away no more of the Stock of this Nation, than is abſolutely ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſary for the ſupply of our Neceſſities. And it would be a great advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage to the Kingdom to be furniſhed with that within our ſelves which we neceſſarily want, and are enforced to depend upon Foreigners for.</p>
               <p>In ſhort, the Prohibition of <hi>Iriſh</hi> Cattel, puts them on a neceſſity, (for ſomething they muſt do with their Cattel, and the product of their Lands, or be utterly deſtroyed) that neceſſity forceth them to In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duſtry; which Induſtry, if not determined with us, but continued or encouraged with Foreigners, the more induſtrious they are, the more pernicious it will be to <hi>England</hi> in all its concerns. For, if the <hi>Iriſh,</hi> by reaſon of their Religion, and the ſenſe of our conquering them, have (as ſome affirm, and I and all Engliſh-men have good reaſon to believe) a natural antipathy againſt us Engliſh-men, and as natural an Affection and Sympathy to and with Foreigners, who are of their own Perſwaſion and Religion; And if Nations grow Intimate, eſpouſe In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt, and mix by Trade and Commerce, it is humbly ſubmitted, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther for the ſecurity of <hi>England,</hi> both in its Government and Trade, it be not adviſeable to annex <hi>Ireland</hi> as a Province to <hi>England,</hi> as our Iſlands abroad are annexed, whereby his Majeſties Revenue of Cuſtoms would be advanced at leaſt 80000 <hi>l. per annum,</hi> which would help to pay the Publick Debts, and do a publick good to the Nation?</p>
               <p>Concerning the Importation of <hi>Weſtphalia</hi>-Hams, I have onely this to ſay, That though Prohibited, yet they are Imported, the King loſeth the Cuſtom of them which formerly he had, the Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chants buy them far cheaper beyond Seas than ever they did; in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> the Subjects pay twice as much as they might have bought them for before the Prohibition; and not any good is done to the Kingdom thereby.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <pb n="21" facs="tcp:53444:12"/>
               <head>VI.</head>
               <p>THe Sixth thing propoſed, is, the Prohibition of <hi>Brandy, Mum, Coffee, Chocoletta</hi> and <hi>Tea,</hi> and the ſuppreſſing <hi>Coffe-Houſes.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Theſe greatly hinder the Conſumption of <hi>Barley, Malt</hi> and <hi>Wheat,</hi> the Product of our Land, and thereby bring down the prices of theſe Grains, conſequently the Rents of Land; to the ruine of Tenants, who cannot ſell their Corn, when they have it; and of Landlords, whoſe Rents Tenants are not able to pay, becauſe they have no vent for the Product of their Farms.</p>
               <p>There is (as I am (upon ſtrict Enquiry of the moſt knowing per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons) informed) ſo vaſt a quantity of <hi>Brandy, Mum, Coffee, Tea</hi> and <hi>Spaniſh Chocoletta,</hi> every year imported into <hi>England,</hi> and conſumed here, that reckoning the <hi>Brandy</hi> to be ſold at two pence the Quartern, and no more (whereas moſt of it by retail is ſold for three pence) the Mum at ſix pence a Quart, and the <hi>Coffee, Tea, Chocoletta,</hi> at the rates they are uſually ſold for, yet is there expended by the Subjects yearly in theſe drinks above 400000 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>If theſe Liquors were prohibited, then would there be made in <hi>England,</hi> with our Wheat, or Malt, ſuch quantities of Brandy, or a Spirit equal to it, and of Mum alſo, as would, in all probability, occaſion the Conſumption of at leaſt two or three hundred thouſand Quarters of Wheat and Malt every year more than now is conſumed; and that would raiſe the price of the Commodity, and thereby keep up the Rent of Lands, which every year falls for want of a Conſumption of the Product thereof: And the Prohibition of Brandy would be otherwiſe advantageous to the Kingdom, and prevent the deſtruction of His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Subjects; many of whom have been kill'd by drinking thereof, it not agreeing with their Conſtitutions. How many inſtances have we had yearly of mens dying ſuddenly, after drinking of Brandy! How many after over-drinking themſelves with this Liquour, have lain languiſhing till they have dyed thereof! Before Brandy (which is now become common, and ſold in every little Alehouſe) came over into <hi>England</hi> in ſuch quanties as now it doth, we drank good Strong Beer and Ale; and all laborious people (which are the far greateſt part of the Kingdom) their bodies requiring, after hard labour, ſome ſtrong drink to refreſh them, did therefore every morning and evening uſe to
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:53444:13"/>drink a pot of Ale, or a flagon of ſtrong Beer: which greatly pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moted the Conſumption of our own Grain, and did them no great prejudice; it hindred not their work, neither did it take away their ſenſes, nor coſt them much money. But now this ſort of people, ſince Brandy is become ſo common, and fold in every little houſe (a ſmall quantity coſting them three pence) do ſometimes ſpend their days wages in this ſort of Liquor, before they get home in an evening, and thereby impoveriſh their Families; and not only ſo, but frequently by their drinking to exceſs, they are bereft of their ſenſes for two or three days together, ſo that they cannot work.</p>
               <p>In ſhort, Brandy burns the hearts of His Majeſties Subjects out; in few years it hath been the deſtruction and death of ſome thouſands, who if they had kept to Beer and Ale might have received better re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>freſhment therefrom, and now been living to have ſerved the King and their Countrey, and might have help'd to conſume the Manufactures and Proviſions of the Kingdom. And if ſo, then what reaſon can any man give for the Importation thereof? For my own part I declare, I know of none, unleſs it he, becauſe it pays a great Cuſtom or Exciſe to the King And as to that, I anſwer and affirm. That if <hi>Brandy</hi> be prohibited, the Exciſe of the Beer and Ale that would be then con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumed, more than is now, will more than anſwer the duty of <hi>Brandy</hi> that the King ſhall loſe by ſuch Prohibition as is deſired (admitting that all the <hi>Brandy</hi> imported paid the duty impoſed, when as not one half thereof is paid for, the ſame being ſtolm; inſomuch, that when the duty to the King was four ſhillings <hi>per</hi> Gallon, <hi>Brandy</hi> was ſold for three ſhillings, which was twelve pence leſs than the Kings Duty:) But admitting that if <hi>Brandy</hi> ſhould be prohibited, the additional Exciſe of Ale and Beer would not anſwer the Kings loſe he ſhall ſuſtain there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by; and taking it for granted, that our Engliſh Conſtitutions are now ſo accuſtomed to <hi>Brandy,</hi> that it is become abſolutely neceſſary for them to uſe the ſame, or ſome Liquor like it: If it be ſo, then from our Malt and Wheat may be extracted a Spirit equally as good, if not for our Conſtitutions much better than <hi>Brandy:</hi> And then laying a ſmall duty (as a penny a Gallon) upon <hi>low Wines,</hi> will more than anſwer what the additional Exciſe ſhall fall ſhort of to the King, yea, and very much exceed what he ſhall loſe by the Prohibition deſired. And in as much as nothing is ſo much wanting in <hi>England</hi> as people; Therefore all means poſſible, in point of Prudence and Policy, ought to be uſed to preſerve the lives and healths of thoſe we have: But the Importing of <hi>Brandy</hi> hath deſtroyed many, is like to deſtroy more; <hi>ergo,</hi> it ought
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:53444:13"/>to be prohibited. And the rather, in regard that <hi>Brandy</hi> comes from <hi>France;</hi> and whatever we import from <hi>France,</hi> ready money is paid for the ſame, or for the greateſt part thereof: For although we impoſe but between Four and Ten pound <hi>per cent.</hi> upon any of the Manufacturies or Commodities of the growth of <hi>France,</hi> except the duty upon Wine and Brandy; yet the French King either prohibites the Importation of the Manufactures of <hi>England</hi> into his Dominions, or the ſelling them there, unleſs they be ſealed, for which Seal, a great duty is paid, or elſe he burns them if they are imported, and ſold without ſuch Seal (as he did the Silk Stockings) or impoſeth upon the Importation thereof, a duty of 30, 40, or 50 <hi>l. per cent.</hi> which is double as muchas was impoſed, till within theſe few years laſt paſt; and is in effect a Prohibition: For, when we do Tranſport any thing thither of our Growth or Manufacturies, the French, by reaſon of the high duty impoſed upon them, underſel us; whereby we are neceſſitated to keep our goods till ſpoiled, or bring them back. And if ſo, them plain it is, that whatſoever we have from <hi>France,</hi> ready money goes for the ſame: So that by a moderate com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putation, they have at leaſt 400000 <hi>l. per annum</hi> in money from us<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> which is a vaſt prejudice to <hi>England,</hi> and a great enriching to <hi>France</hi> who impoſe upon us, not only vaſt proportions of their <hi>Brandy</hi> and Wines, but alſo of their Silks, Stuffs, Ribbons, Laces, Points, and divers other things, whereby our Manufacturers in <hi>England</hi> are ruined, and the Treaſure of the Nation exhauſted. I know it will be ſaid, that we lay far greater Impoſitions upon their Wines and Brandy, than they do upon any of our Manufactures, and it is true, that we do ſo. But conſider, that whatever duty we lay upon Wines, is laid upon the King of <hi>Englands</hi> own Subjects, they pay it, and ſuch duty doth not hinder the Importation thereof; for more comes in now then ever there did when the duty was not half ſo high, and the <hi>French</hi> force the Engliſh to pay more for their Wines than ever they paid before. But the Impoſitions laid by the King of <hi>France</hi> upon our Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nufactures, have ſtopt us from ſending any thing conſiderable thither, whereas before ſuch duties impoſed, we ſent great quantities: So that in a few years, if not prevented, the very Commerce with <hi>France</hi> is like to deſtroy <hi>England.</hi> As for <hi>Brunſwick</hi> Mum, I am ſure we brew as ſtrong in <hi>England</hi> as they do there, and yet afford to ſell it for half the price they ſell theirs for; therefore there is no neceſſity of the Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portation thereof, to ſupply any defect we have here, conſequently, 'tis not fit to be encouraged, becauſe it hinders the Conſumption of the Grain of this Kingdom.</p>
               <pb n="24" facs="tcp:53444:14"/>
               <p>And for <hi>Coffee, Tea</hi> and <hi>Chocoletta,</hi> I know no good they do; only the places where they are ſold are convenient for perſons to meet in, ſit half a day, and diſcourſe with all Companies that come in, of State-matters, talking of news, and broaching of lyes, arraigning the judgements and diſcretions of their Governors, cenſuring all their Councels, and inſinuating into the people a prejudice againſt them; ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tolling and magnifying their own parts, knowledge and wiſdom, and decrying that of their<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Rulers; which, if ſuffered too long, may prove pernicious and deſtructive. But ſay there were nothing of this in the caſe, yet have theſe <hi>Coffee</hi> Houſes done great miſchiefs to the Nation, undone many of the Kings Subjects; for they being very great Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies to Diligence and Induſtry, have been the ruine of many ſerious and hopeful young Gentlemen and Tradeſmen, who before they fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quented theſe places, were diligent Students or Shopkeepers, extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ordinary husbands of their time, as well as money: but ſince theſe Houſes have been ſet up, under pretence of good husbandry, to avoid ſpending above one peny or two pence at a time, have got to theſe Coffee Houſes; where meeting Friends, they have ſate talking three or four hours, after which a freſh acquaintance appearing (and ſo one after an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other all day long) hath begotten freſh diſcourſe; So that frequent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly they have ſtaid five or ſix hours together in one of them: All which time their Studies or Shops have been neglected, their Buſineſs left un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>done, their Servants been truſted, and an opportunity given them thereby to be idle and deceitful; the taking of money in many of theſe mens ſhops hath been hindred, and their Cuſtomers gone away diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pleaſed: How many by theſe means have received great loſſes and diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>advantages in their Trade! and by accuſtoming themſelves to theſe houſes, have made it ſo habitual to them, that they cannot forbear them, though, together with their Familes, they are ruined thereby. Theſe Houſes being very many of them profeſſed Bawdy Houſes, more expenſive than other houſes, are become ſcandalous for a man to be ſeen in them; which Gentlemen not knowing, do frequently fall into them by chance, and ſo their Reputation is drawn into queſtion thereby.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <pb n="25" facs="tcp:53444:14"/>
               <head>VII.</head>
               <p>THe Seventh Propoſal, That the multitude of <hi>Stage-Coaches</hi> and <hi>Caravans,</hi> now travelling upon the Roads, may all, or moſt of them, be ſuppreſſed; eſpecially theſe within 40, 50, or 60 Miles of <hi>London,</hi> where they are no way neceſſary. And that a due Regulation be made of ſuch as ſhall be thought fit to be continued.</p>
               <p>Theſe <hi>Coaches</hi> and <hi>Caravans</hi> are one of the greateſt miſchiefs that hath hapned of late years to the Kingdom, miſchievous to the Publick, deſtructive to Trade, and prejudicial to Lands.</p>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Firſt;</hi> By deſtroying the Breed of good Horſes, the Strength of the Nation, and making Men careleſs of attaining to good Horſemanſhip, a thing ſo uſeful and commendable in a Gentleman.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Secondly;</hi> By hindring the Breed of Watermen, who are the Nurſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry for Seamen, and they the Bulwark of the Kingdom.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Thirdly;</hi> By leſſening of his Majeſties Revenues.</item>
               </list>
               <p>For the firſt of theſe; <hi>Stage-Coaches</hi> prevent the breed of good Horſes, deſtroy thoſe that are bred, and effeminate his Majeſties Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects, who having uſed themſelves to travel in them, have neither at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained skill themſelves, nor bred up their Children to good Horſeman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, whereby they are rendred uncapable of ſerving their Countrey on Horſeback, if occaſion ſhould require and call for the ſame; for, here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by the become weary and liſtleſs when they ride a few miles, and un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>willing to get on Horſeback; not able to endure Froſt, Snow, or Rain, or to lodg in the Fields; and what reaſon, ſave only their uſing them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves ſo tenderly, and their riding in theſe <hi>Stage-Coaches,</hi> can be given for this their inability?</p>
               <p>What encouragement hath any Man to breed Horſes whilſt theſe Coaches are continued? There is ſuch a lazy habit of body upon Men, that they, to indulge themſelves, ſave their fine Cloaths, and keep themſelves clean and dry, will ride lolling in one of them, and endure all the Inconveniences of that manner of travelling rather than ride on Horſeback: So that if any Man ſhould continue his Breed, he muſt be one that is a great lover of them, and reſolve to keep and pleaſe his own fancy with them; otherwiſe moſt certainly he (as moſt Breeders already have done) will give over his breeding.</p>
               <p>There is not the fourth part of Saddle-Horſes, either bred or kept
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:53444:15"/>now in <hi>England,</hi> that was before theſe Coaches were ſet up, and would be again if they were ſuppreſt. Nor is there any occaſion for breeding or keeping ſuch Horſes, whilſt the Coaches are continued.</p>
               <p>For, will any Man keep a Horſe for himſelf, and another for his Man, all the year, for to ride one or two Journeys, that at pleaſure, when he hath occaſion, can ſlip to any place where his buſineſs lies, for two, three, or four ſhillings, if within twenty miles of <hi>London,</hi> and ſo proportionably into any part of <hi>England.</hi> No, there is no Man, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs ſome Noble Soul, that ſcorns and abhors being confined to ſo igno<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, baſe, and a ſordid way of travelling, as theſe Coaches oblige him un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to, and who prefers a publick Good before his own eaſe and advantage, that will breed or keep ſuch Horſes. Neither are there near ſo many Coach-Horſes either bred or kept in <hi>England</hi> now, as there were Sad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dle-Horſes formerly, there being no occaſion for them, the Kingdom being ſupplyed with a far leſs number. For, formerly, every Man that had occaſion to travel many Journeys yearly, or to ride up and down, kept Horſes for himſelf and Servants, and ſeldom rid without one or two Men; But now ſince every Man can have a paſſage into every place he is to travel unto, or to ſome place within a few miles of that part he deſigns to go unto, They have left keeping of Horſes, and travel without Servants; And <hi>York, Cheſter,</hi> and <hi>Exeter</hi> Stage-Coaches, each of them with forty Horſes a piece, carry eighteen Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſengers a week from <hi>London</hi> to either of theſe places; and in like man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner as many in return from theſe places to <hi>London;</hi> which comes in the whole to 1872 in the year. Now take it for granted, That all that are carried from <hi>London</hi> to thoſe places, are the ſame that are brought back, yet are there 936 Paſſengers carried by forty Horſes; whereas were it not for theſe Coaches, at leaſt 500 Horſes would be required to perform this Work. Take the ſort Stages within twenty or thirty miles of <hi>London,</hi> each Coach with four Horſes carries ſix Paſſengers a day, which are 36 in a week, 1872 a year; If theſe Coaches were ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſt, can any Man imagine theſe 1872 Paſſengers and their Servants could be carried by four Horſes? Then reckon your Coaches within ten miles of <hi>London,</hi> that go backward and forward every day, and they carry double the number every year; and ſo proportionably your ſhorter Stages within three, four, or five miles of <hi>London.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>There are Stage-Coaches that go to almoſt every Town within 20 or 25 miles of <hi>London,</hi> wherein Paſſengers are carried at ſo low Rates, that moſt perſons in and about <hi>London,</hi> and in <hi>Middleſex, Eſſex, Kent,</hi> and <hi>Surry,</hi> Gentlemen, Merchants, and other Traders that have occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:53444:15"/>to ride do make uſe of; ſome to keep Fairs and Markets; others to viſit Friends, and to, and from their Countrey-houſes, or about other buſineſs, who before theſe Coaches did ſet up, kept a Horſe or two of their own, but now have given over keeping the ſame; ſo that by computation there are not ſo many by ten thouſand Horſes kept now in theſe Parts, as there were before Stage-Coaches ſet up: By which means breeding of good Pad-Nags is diſcouraged, and Coach-Horſes that are bred, by cruelty and ill uſage of Stagers are deſtroyed.</p>
               <p n="2">2ly, Thoſe Coaches hinder the breeding of Water-men, and much diſcourage thoſe that are bred; for there being Stage-Coaches ſet up unto every little Town upon the River of <hi>Thames,</hi> on both ſides the Water, from <hi>London</hi> as high as <hi>Windſor</hi> and <hi>Maidenhead,</hi> &amp;c. And ſo from <hi>London</hi>-Bridg to and below <hi>Graves-end,</hi> and alſo to every little Town within a mile or two of the Water-ſide. Theſe are they who carry all the Letters, little Bundles, and Paſſengers, which before they ſet up, were carried by Water, and kept Water-men in a full Employ, and occaſioned their increaſe, (whereof there never was more need than now); And yet by theſe Coaches, they of all others are moſt diſcoura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged and dejected, eſpecally our Weſtern and below-Bridg Water-men; they having little or nothing to do, ſometimes not a Fare in a week; ſo that they dare not take Apprentices, the Work they have not an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwering the charge they are at in keeping themſelves and Families. The conſequence whereof is like to prove ſad in a ſhort time, unleſs ſpeedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly prevented, eſpecially if theſe Wars continue, and we happen to loſe ſo many yearly of thoſe that are bred, as of late years we have done. But if theſe Coaches were down, Water-men as formerly would have Work, and be encouraged to take Apprentices, whereby their number would every year greatly encreaſe.</p>
               <p n="3">3ly, It prejudiceth his Majeſty in his Revenue of Exciſe: For now four or five travel in a Coach together, and twenty or thirty in a Cara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>van, Gentlemen and Ladies, without any Servants, conſume little Drink on the Road, yet pay as much at every Inn, as if their Servants were with them, which is the Tapſters gain, and his Majeſties loſs: But if Travellers would, as formerly they did, Travel on Horſeback, then no Perſons of Quality would ride without their Servants: And it is they that occaſion the Conſumption of Beer and Ale on the Roads, and ſo would advance his Majeſties Revenue. I know it will be Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jected, There are as many People now as will be when Coaches are down, and they drink where every they are; Therefore no matter whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther they drink at Home or on the Road, ſince the Conſumption will
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:53444:16"/>be the ſame; how can the Kings Revenue then be advanced by Servants travelling with their Maſters or Miſtreſſes, more than it is already? The anſwer is plain; at home they drink ſmall or ſtrong drink brewed by their Maſters that pay no Exciſe, but whatever they drink at Inns pays the Kings duties: And all Inn-keepers do declare, that they ſell not half the drink, nor pay the King ½ the Exciſe they did before theſe coaches ſet up.</p>
               <p n="2">2ly. Theſe Coaches and Caravaus are deſtructive to the Trade and Manufactories of the Kingdom, have impoveriſhed and ruined many thouſands of Families, whoſe ſubſiſtence depended upon the Manufactu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring of Wool and Leather, two of the Staple-Commodities of the Kingdom: For, before theſe Coaches were ſet up, Travellers rode on Horſeback, and men had Boots, Spurs, Saddles, Bridles, Sadle-clothes, and good riding Suits, Coats and Cloaks, Stockings and Hats; whereby the Wool and Leather of the Kingdom was conſumed, and the poor people ſet at work by Carding, Combing, Spinning, Knitting, Weaving, Fulling: And your <hi>Cloth Workers, Drapers, Taylors, Saddlers, Tanners, Curriers, Shoemakers, Spurriers, Lorayners, Felt-makers,</hi> had a good im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy, were full of work, got money, lived handſomely, and help'd with their Families to Conſume the Proviſions and Manufactures of the Kingdoms: But by means of theſe Coaches, theſe Trades, beſides many others depending upon them, are become almoſt uſeleſs<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and they, with their Families, reduced to great neceſſity; inſomuch, that many thouſands of them are caſt upon the Pariſhes wherein they dwell, for a Maintenance. Beſides, it is a great hurt to the <hi>Girdlers, Sword-Cutlers, Gunſmiths</hi> and <hi>Trunk-makers;</hi> moſt Gentlemen, before they travelled in their Coaches, uſing to ride with Swords, Belts, Piſtols, Holſters, Portmantues and Hat-caſes, which in theſe Coaches they have little or no occaſion for: For, when they rode on Horſeback, they rode in one Suit, carried another to wear when they came to their journeys end, or lay by the way: But in Coaches, a Silk-Suit, and an Indian Gown, with a Saſh, Silk-Stockings, Beaver-Hats men ride in, and carry no other with them, becauſe they eſcape the wet and dirt, which on Horſe-back they cannot avoid; whereas in two or three journeys on Horſeback, theſe cloaths and hats were wont to be ſpoiled: Which done, they were forced to have new very often; and that encreaſed the Conſumption of the Manufactures, and the imployment of the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nufacturers, which travelling in Coaches doth no way do. And if they were women, that travelled, they uſed to have Safeguards, and Hoods, Side-ſaddles and Pillions, with Strappins, Saddle or Pillion-cloths, which (for the moſt part) were either laced or imbroydered; to the
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:53444:16"/>making of which there went many ſeveral Trades, ſeeing there is not one Side-Saddle with the furniture made, but before it be furniſhed, there are at leaſt thirty ſeveral Trades have a ſhare in the making there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, moſt of which are either deſtroyed, or greatly prejudiced by the Abatement of their Trade: Which being bred unto, and having ſerved ſeven years Apprentiſhip to learn, they know not what other courſe to take for a Livelyhood. And beſides all theſe Inferior Handy-Craftſmen, there are the <hi>Mercers, Silkmen, Lace-Men, Milliners, Linnen and Woollen Drapers, Haberdaſhers,</hi> and divers other Eminent Trades, that receive great prejudice by this way of Travelling: For the Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers ſold Silk and Stuff in great quantities for Safeguards, Hoods, and Riding Clothes for women; by which means the <hi>Silk-Twiſters, Winders, Throſeters, Weavers</hi> and <hi>Dyers,</hi> had a fuller Imployment, the Silk-men ſold-more Lace and Imbroidery, which kept the <hi>Silver-Wyre-Drawers, Lace-makers</hi> and <hi>Imbroyderers.</hi> And at leaſt ten Trades more were imployed: The Linnen-Draper ſold more Linnen, not only to Sadlers to make up Sadles, but to Travellers for their own uſe, no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing wearing out Linnen more than riding. <hi>Woollen-Drapers</hi> ſold more Cloth than now; <hi>Sadlers</hi> uſed before theſe Coaches were ſet up, to buy 3 or 400 <hi>l.</hi> worth of Cloth apiece in a year, nay ſome Five hundred and a Thouſand pounds worth, which they cut out into Saddles and Pillion-Cloths; though now there is no Sadler can diſpoſe of One hundred pounds worth of Cloth in a year in his Trade. The <hi>Milliners</hi> and <hi>Haberdaſhers,</hi> they alſo ſold more Ribbons, Gloves, Hoods, Scarfs, and other things belonging to their Trade; the duſt, dirt and rain, and riding on Horſe-back, ſpoiling and wearing them out, much more than travelling in a Coach: And on Horſeback theſe things were apter to be loſt than in a Coach.</p>
               <p>Trade is a great Myſterie, and one Trade depends upon another: Were it not too tedious, I could ſhew you how many ſeveral Trades there are that go to the making of every one of the things aforementi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned, and demonſtrate, that there is ſcarcely a Trade in <hi>England,</hi> but what is one way or other concerned and prejudiced by theſe Stage-Coaches, eſpecially the Countrey-Trade all over <hi>England:</hi> For, paſſage to <hi>London</hi> being ſo eaſie, Gentlemen come to <hi>London</hi> oftner than they need, and their Ladies either with them, or having the conveniencies of theſe Coaches, quickly follow them. And when they are there, they muſt be in the Mode, have all the new Faſhions, buy all their Cloaths there, and go to Plays, Balls and Treats, where they get ſuch a habit of Jollity, and a love to Gayety and Pleaſure, that nothing afterwards.
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:53444:17"/>in the Countrey will ſerve them, if ever they ſhould fix their minds to live there again: But they muſt have all from <hi>London,</hi> whatever it coſts.</p>
               <p>And there is one grand miſchief happens to the Countrey thereby; for Gentlemen drain the Countrey of all the money they can get, bring it to <hi>London,</hi> and ſpend it there: Whereas if they ſtayed at home, bought their Cloaths and other Commodities, of their Neighbours, money would be kept circulating amongſt them; and Chapmen that have ſerved Apprenticeſhips, and ſet up near them, would have a good Trade, pay their Rents, and live handſomely, the Trade be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>twixt them and the City of <hi>London</hi> would be renewed, Countrey La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies would be as well pleaſed (provided they be kept from <hi>London</hi>) as if they had all the rich Clothes, Modes and Faſhions, vainly and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>travagantly invented and worn in the City, aſſoon as they have them there; and Gentlemen would not only ſave the money they ſpend in Journeys to buy Cloaths, but have as good as need to be worn in the Countrey, at eaſier rates than they muſt pay at <hi>London,</hi> if they buy when the Faſhion comes firſt up.</p>
               <p n="3">3ly. Theſe Coaches and Caravans, hinders the Conſumption of all ſort of Proviſions for Man and Beaſt, thereby bringing down the Rents of Lands. For inſtance, a Coach with four Horſes carries ſix Paſſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers, a Caravan with four or five Horſes, carries twenty or five and twenty: Theſe, when they come to their Inn, club together for a Diſh or two of Meat, and having no Servants with them, ſpend not above twelve pence, or ſixteen pence apiece at a place; yet perhaps foul four, five or ſix pair of ſheets. Horſes they have none, but what draw them; and for thoſe, the Coach-men agree with the Innkeeper before hand, to have their Hay and Oats at ſo low a rate, that he loſeth by them, and is forced to beat down the price of them in the Market, yet muſt let the Coachman have them for what he pleaſeth; otherwiſe he carries his Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſengers to other Inns: by which means the Inholders get little or nothing, cannot pay their Rent, nor hold their Inns, without great Abatements; Two third parts of what they formerly paid, is in ſome places abated. Upon ſuch accounts as theſe, Innholders where theſe Coaches do come, are undone: And if ſo, ſince moſt Travellers travel in Coaches, what muſt become of all the reſt of the Inns on the Roads where theſe Coaches ſtay not? Believe it, they are a conſiderable number, take all the grand Roads in <hi>England,</hi> as, <hi>York, Exeter, Cheſter,</hi> &amp;c. There are about 500 Inns on each Road, and theſe Coaches do not call at fifteen or ſixteen of them; then what can follow, but that the reſt be undone, and their Landlords loſe their Rents?</p>
               <pb n="31" facs="tcp:53444:17"/>
               <p>But were theſe Coaches and Caravans down, and travelling on Horſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>back again come into faſhion, firſt, every Paſſenger that now travels in Coach, would have one Horſe at leaſt; many of them, one, two or three Servants with them, who now ride ſneaking without any At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tendants at all; whereby, in all probability, according to moderate Computation, there would be at leaſt forty or fifty horſes upon the Road, inſtead of nine or ten that draw the Coach and Caravan.</p>
               <p n="2">2ly. Theſe Travellers would diſperſe themſelves into the ſeveral Inns upon the Road, each man where he could find the beſt Entertainment; whereby Trade would be diffuſed, Innholders be enabled to pay their Rents, and encouraged to provide accommodations fit for the reception of Gentlemen.</p>
               <p n="3">3. Moſt Horſes go to graſs in the Summer time, which would raiſe the Rents of Paſture-Lands about Cities and Corporations, and other Towns upon the Roads, above what formerly they were; which of late years, by means of thoſe Coaches, have fallen half in half, even in <hi>Middleſex,</hi> and other places adjoyning to <hi>London</hi> it ſelf: And n<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> other reaſon for it can be given but this, That Citizens and Gentlemen about the City, do not keep Horſes as formerly they did: Neither doth there now come a fixth part of the Horſes to <hi>London</hi> that uſed to do; but if Stage Coaches be ſuppreſt, there will be a neceſſity for men to apply themſelves to the breeding, keeping and uſing Horſes as former<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly they did; and it will neceſſarily occaſion the Conſumption of five times the quantity of Hay, Straw and Horſe-Corn that now is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumed; whereby Farmers will have a vent for their Commodities, and be enabled to pay their Rents; for, not only will there then be four times the number of Horſes travelling upon the Roads as there are now, but in the City of <hi>London,</hi> and all the great Towns in <hi>England,</hi> there would be great numbers of good Horſes kept by Gentlemen, Merchants and Tradeſmen for their own uſes; and by others alſo, to let out to hire to ſuch as ſhall have occaſion to ride, and keep not Horſes of their own.</p>
               <p>It is very obſerveable, that before theſe Coaches were ſet up, what with the Horſes kept by Merchants, and other Tradeſmen, and Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen in or near <hi>London,</hi> and the Travellers Horſes that came to <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> That City ſpent all the <hi>Hay, Straw, Beans, Peaſe,</hi> and <hi>Oats,</hi> that could be ſpared within twenty or thirty miles thereof; And for a fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther ſupply, had vaſt quantities from <hi>Henly,</hi> and other Weſtern parts, and from below <hi>Graves-end</hi> by Water; beſides many Ships Lading of Beans from <hi>Hull,</hi> and of Oats from <hi>Lynn</hi> and <hi>Boſton;</hi> and then Oats,
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:53444:18"/>and Hay, and other Horſe-Meat, would bear a good price in that Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ket, which was the Standard for all the Markets in <hi>England;</hi> But now, ſince theſe Coaches ſet up, eſpecially in ſuch multitudes, and thoſe ſo nigh <hi>London, London</hi> cannot conſume what grows within twenty miles of it. But if they were down, the Conſumption in <hi>London</hi> would quickly be as great as ever, and that would raiſe the price of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities, advance the price of Lands, and cauſe Rents to be well paid again; Not only would every Traveller that now rides in a Coach, travel on Horſeback, if Coaches were down, and ſome of them with two or three Servants, and ſo occaſion a greater Conſumption of the Proviſions for Cattel: But further every of theſe ſeveral Travellers, who before clubbed together for a Diſh or two of Meat, would have one, two, or three Diſhes of Meat for himſelf and his Servants; which would occaſion the Conſumption of ſix times as much Beef, Veal, Mut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ton, Lamb, and all ſorts of Fiſh, Fowl, Poultry, and other Proviſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons, as is now conſumed on the Roads: And ſuch Conſumption would raiſe the price of Lands, and cauſe better payment of Rents; eſpeci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally if it be conſidered, That not only will the Conſumption be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſed by thoſe that travel the Roads; but ten-times more would be ſpent by thoſe who would be imployed in the making thoſe things that Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vellers muſt have when they ride; who, if they have work, and can earn Money, will Eat and Drink of the beſt, as formerly they did, when ſeveral Handicraft Tradeſmen in <hi>London</hi> kept 20, 30, or 40 Journeymen at work, ſpent a quarter of Beef, and a Carcaſs of Mutton in a week in their Houſes; who ſince theſe Coaches ſet up, have fallen to a couple of Apprentices; and though as eminent of their Trade as any about <hi>London,</hi> yet can hardly earn Bread to put into their heads. If it be ſo then, that <hi>Running Stage-Coaches</hi> and <hi>Caravans</hi> are ſo injurious to the Publick, deſtructive to Trade, and the occaſion of the fall of Rents, it would be worth time to conſider what is in them worthy of their being coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenanced and deſired; And whether the Inconveniencies be not much greater than the Conveniencies men receive by them. If this way of travelling were the way that of all wayes appeared moſt beneficial, leaſt expenſive, conducing to Health, advantagious to men in their buſineſs, abſolutely neceſſary to ſome, uſeful to others, and impoſed upon none; There were ſome reaſon for mens being in love with them; but if the contrary be apparent, then what madneſs poſſeſſeth men to court their Inconveniencies and Miſchiefs? Let us examine theſe things.</p>
               <p>Men receive not the greateſt benefit by travelling in theſe Coaches<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> For can that way be beneficial to any that hinders and deſtroyes Trade,
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:53444:18"/>prevents the Conſumption of the Proviſions and Manufactures of the Kingdom, and thereby lowers the Rents of Landlords?</p>
               <p>For <hi>Firſt,</hi> Can a Gentleman receive benefit or advantage by ſaving 5 <hi>l. per Ann.</hi> in a journey, when by his manner of travelling he lowers his own Rents three times as much in a year as he ſaves by his Jour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys, by countenancing that kind of conveyance that hinders the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumption of the products of his own Eſtate, and thereby makes his Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants unable to pay their Rents?</p>
               <p n="2">2ly, Is it to be believed, That a Tradeſman arrives at any profit by theſe Coaches, though he ſhould ſave a little Money when he rides in them, that he muſt neceſſarily expend if he travels on Horſeback? No, for this manner of travelling hinders the Sale of thoſe Commodities they deal in; of which much more would be conſumed than is, if ſuch Coaches were down, and by the Sale whereof they would get much more than they ſave by confining themſelves to travelling as aforeſaid; ſo that plainly it is their intereſt to promote that way of travelling, that tends to the greateſt Conſumption of the Manufacturies or Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities wherein they deal.</p>
               <p n="3">3ly, The Husbandmen, who live by the ſweat of their Brows, in manuring the Eſtates of the Gentry, they are undone by this eaſie car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage; for it hinders their ſelling their Corn, Hay, and Straw, and other the products of their Farms, and brings down the price of what they ſell, thereby rendring them unable to pay their Rents, or to hold their Farms without conſiderable abatements: which if not given them, their Lands are thrown up into the Landlords hands, and little or no benefit made by them.</p>
               <p n="4">4ly, The Graſiers, they complain for want of a Vent for their Cattel, which they had before theſe Coaches were erected; Not that I do ima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gine Coaches to be the only reaſon of the want of that Conſumption, though it be evident they go far in the promoting that miſchief; for the want of People in <hi>England,</hi> the loſs of many thouſands from a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt us of late years, and the leaving of eating off Suppers by thoſe that are left alive, go a great way therein. But theſe two may be eaſily remedied; The former by the <hi>General Act of Naturalization,</hi> and <hi>Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berty of Conſcience,</hi> propoſed before, which would bring all Foreigners in amongſt us; The latter, by mens ſpending leſs in Taverns, Playes, and Balls, and keeping up in lieu thereof, the ancient laudable Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomes of <hi>England,</hi> of good Houſe-keeping, and thereby relieving the Poor. Half the Money that Gentlemen idly ſpend in Taverns upon <hi>French</hi> Wines, for which the Coin of the Kingdom is exhauſted, or
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:53444:19"/>upon Playes, Bills, treating Miſtreſſes, fine Clothes, Toyes from <hi>France,</hi> or other Foreign parts, would defray the charges of having good Sup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers every night; whereby the product of our own Lands would be conſumed, and that would raiſe Rents: Nay, I am verily perſwaded, if it were duly conſidered, and that all men, as formerly, would fall to eating of Suppers, at leaſt to dreſſing of them; and when dreſt, if they eat not themſelves, would give them to the Poor, the increaſe of the Conſumption would raiſe the Rents of Lands, as much above what now they do go at (at leaſt in moſt places of <hi>England</hi>) as would de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fray the charges of thoſe Suppers; If ſo, would it not then be of great advantage to Men in their Eſtates, and to the Kingdom in general?</p>
               <p>But to proceed; If the Gentlement, the Tradeſmen, the Husband<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, the Graſier, be not benefited by this travelling, I am ſure the laſt ſort of Travellers; To wit,</p>
               <p>The Poor, they cannot be profited thereby; For Waggons, or the Long Coaches firſt invented, and ſtill in uſe, would be moſt for their intereſt to travel in, being far leſs expenſive than the other; ſo that theſe Running Coaches are not moſt beneficial to every ſort of Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vellers.</p>
               <p>Secondly, Men do not travel in theſe Coaches with leſs expence of Money or Time than on Horſeback: For, on Horſeback they may tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vel faſter; and if they pleaſe (all things duly conſidered) with as lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle, if not leſs charges.</p>
               <p>For inſtance, From <hi>London</hi> to <hi>Exeter, Cheſter,</hi> or <hi>York,</hi> you pay 40 ſhillings apiece in Summer time, 45 ſhillings in Winter for your Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſage; and as much from thoſe places back to <hi>London:</hi> beſides, in the Journey they change Coachmen four times; and there are few Paſſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers but gives 12 pence to each Coachman at the end of his Stage, which comes to 8 ſhillings in the Journey backward and forward, and at leaſt 3 ſhillings comes to each Paſſengers ſhare to pay for the Coach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mens Drink on the Road; ſo that in Summer time the Paſſage back<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward and forward to any of theſe places, coſts 4 <hi>l.</hi> 11 <hi>s.</hi> in the Winter 5 <hi>l</hi> 1 <hi>s.</hi> and this only for eight dayes riding in the Summer, and 12 in the Winter. Then when the Paſſengers come to <hi>London,</hi> they muſt have Lodgings, which perhaps may coſt them five or ſix ſhillings a week, and that in fourteen dayes amounts unto 10 or 12 <hi>s.</hi> which makes the 4 <hi>l.</hi> 11 <hi>s.</hi> either 5 <hi>l.</hi> 1 <hi>s.</hi> or 5 <hi>l.</hi> 3 <hi>s.</hi> or the 5 <hi>l.</hi> 1 <hi>s.</hi> 5 <hi>l.</hi> 11 <hi>s.</hi> or 5 <hi>l.</hi> 13 <hi>s.</hi> beſides the inconveniency of having Meat from the Cooks, at double the price they might have it for in Inns. But if Stage-Coaches were
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:53444:19"/>down, and men travelled again as formerly on Horſeback, then when they came into their Inns they would pay nothing for Lodgings; And as there would excellent Horſes be bred and kept by Gentlement for their own uſe, ſo would there be by others that would keep them on purpoſe to Lett; which would, as formerly, be let at 10 or 12 <hi>s. per</hi> week, and in many places for 6, 8, or 9 <hi>s. per</hi> week: but admitting the loweſt price to be 12 <hi>s.</hi> if a Man comes from <hi>York, Exeter,</hi> or <hi>Cheſter,</hi> to <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don,</hi> be five dayes a coming, five dayes going, and ſtay twelve dayes in <hi>London</hi> to diſpatch his buſineſs, (which is the moſt that Countrey Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men uſually to ſtay) all this would be but three weeks; ſo that his Horſe-hire would come but to 1 <hi>l.</hi> 16 <hi>s.</hi> his Horſe-meat at 1 <hi>s.</hi> 2 <hi>d.</hi> a day, (one with another) which is the higheſt that can be reckoned up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and will come but to 1 <hi>l.</hi> 5 <hi>s.</hi> in all 3 <hi>l.</hi> 1 <hi>s.</hi> ſo that there would be at leaſt 40 or 50 <hi>s.</hi> ſaved of what Coach-hire and Lodgings will coſt him; which would go a great way in paying for Riding-Clothes, Stockings, Hats, Boots, Spurs, and other Accoutrements for riding; and in my poor opinion, would be far better ſpent in the buying of theſe things, by the making whereof the poor would be ſet at work, and kept from being burthenſom to the Pariſh, than to give it to thoſe Stage-Coachmen, to indulge that lazy, idle, habit of Body, that men, by conſtant riding in theſe Coaches, have brought upon themſelves: Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides, if thus their Money were ſpent, they would ſave a great deal, which now (if Men of any Eſtates) they pay for relief of thoſe poor, who, for want of the work they had before thoſe Coaches were ſet up, and might have again if they were put down, are fallen upon the ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Pariſhes wherein they live, for maintenance: which charge would be quickly taken off if they were reſtored to their work. Thus in pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion may a Man ſave from all longer or ſhorter Stages. For in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance, from <hi>Northampton</hi> men pay for paſſage in Coach to <hi>London</hi> 16 <hi>s.</hi> and ſo much back; from <hi>Briſtol</hi> 25 <hi>s.</hi> from <hi>Bath</hi> 20 <hi>s.</hi> from <hi>Saliſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bury</hi> 20 or 25 <hi>s.</hi> from <hi>Redding</hi> 7 <hi>s.</hi> the like ſums back, and ſo in pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion for longer or ſhorter Stages. Judge them, whether men may not hire Horſes cheaper than 5 <hi>s.</hi> a day; I am ſure they may for half the money, eſpecially if Coaches were down, that men might receive encouragement; for, then there would be, as formerly, in all great Cities and Towns of <hi>England,</hi> good and ſufficient numbers of able Horſes kept to Lett, and ſuch a correſpondency would be between all the places, that a Man in any Town ſhall have a Horſe to ride to what place he pleaſeth, and liberty to leave him when he comes to his Jour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys end, without farther charge, till he have diſpatched his buſineſs:
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:53444:20"/>which done, he may at the ſame place hire one to carry him back and be gone, without waiting a week or ten dayes after his Affairs are end<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, at vaſt charges, meerly for a paſſage in a Coach; as many of theſe Gentlemen are forced to do, who pretend it a point of good Husban<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dry to travel in them, which hazard nevertheleſs they run, and often find the ſmart of it: They never conſider or account the charge there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, if they did, they would eaſily perceive, that travelling in Coaches is not the way of travelling with leaſt expence.</p>
               <p>Thirdly, Travelling in theſe Coathes can neither prove advantagi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous to mens Health or Buſineſs: For, what advantage is it to Man's Health, to be called out of their Beds into theſe Coaches, an hour be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore day in the morning, to be hurried in them from place to place place, till one hour, two, or three within night; inſomuch that after ſitting all day in the Summer time ſtifled with heat, and choaked with the duſt; or the Winter time ſtarving and freezing with cold, or choaked with filthy Fogs, they are often brought into their Inns by Torch-light, when it is too late to ſit up to get a Supper; and next morning they are forced into the Coach ſo early, that they can get no Breakfaſt. What addition is this to mens Health or Buſineſs, to ride all day with ſtrangers, oftentimes ſick, ancient, diſeaſed Perſons, or young Children crying; to whoſe humours they are obliged to be ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject, forced to bear with, and many times are poyſoned with their na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſty Scents, and cripled by the crowd of the Boxes and Bundles.</p>
               <p>Is it for a Man's Health to travel with tired Jades, to be laid faſt in the foul Wayes, and forced to wade up to the knees in mire; afterwards ſit in the cold, till Teams of Horſes can be ſent to pull the Coach out? Is it for their health to travel in rotten Coaches, and to have their Tac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kle, or Pearch, or Axletree broken, and then to wait three or four hours, ſometimes half a day to have them mended again, and then to travel all night to make good their Stage? Is it for Mans pleaſure or ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantagious to their Healths and Buſineſs, to travel with a mixt Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany that he knows not how to converſe with; to be affronted by the rudeneſs of a ſurly, dogged, curſing, ill-natured Coachman, neceſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tated to Lodg or Bait at the worſt Inns on the Road, where there is no accommodation fit for Gentlemen; and this meerly becauſe the Owners of the Inns, and the Coachmen, are agreed together to cheat the Gueſts?</p>
               <p>Is it for the advantage of Buſineſs, That a Man, when he ſets out a Journey, muſt come juſt at their hour, or be left behind: ſo that often he is forced, when one hours ſtaying would finiſh his Buſineſs, to go
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:53444:20"/>out of Town, leave it undone, and make a new Journey about it? Is it for advantage of a Man's Buſineſs, that though he have a Concern of great weight or moment to tranſact upon the Road as he goes along, yet if it lie but a ſtones-caſt out of the Coach-way, the Coachman will not drive thither, nor ſtay for him at any place, except the Baiting or Lodging-places where he calls, where they change Horſes; and there ſtay no longer than he pleaſes neither. To be forced, whatever accident of ſickneſs or illneſs happens, to ride theſe Coachmens Stages, thought ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver ſo late in the night, or elſe to be left in the middle of a Journey in a ſtrange place; is this for the conveniency or advantage of a Man's Healch or Buſineſs? rather the quite contrary; Yet this hath been ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Perſons of good Qualities caſe, though they have offered to pay the whole Coach-hire, all the Paſſengers charges, to have put into an Inn (late at night on this ſide the ſet-Stage) yet have they been denyed, for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced to ride, though in peril of their lives, till midnight: And it is not hard to inſtance in many that have loſt their lives by ſuch uſage.</p>
               <p>All which Inconveniencies, if Stage-Coaches were ſuppreſt, would be remedied, lazy humours be diſcountenanced; and a great conveni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ency indeed it would be, both to Travellers, and the Countrey through which they ride, for Men and Women to travel on Horſeback again.</p>
               <p>For then they may, when their buſineſs is done at one place, pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſently take Horſe and go to another, without loſs of time, or ſtaying for a paſſage in a Coach, ſet out as early in the morning, and take up as ſoon in the evening, and bait as long, and as often by the way, and in what places they pleaſe, make choice of their Company on the Road, avoid ſuch as ſuit not with their tempers, go out of the Roads when, and travel as long or ſhort Journeys as they pleaſe, keep out of Cold, Wet, or Foggs, and take into Inns, when the weather is not fit to tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vel in, and ſo preſerve their Healths. And by this means great ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantages would happen, for then all Towns, and every Inn, would have ſomething to do, Trade would be more diffuſed, many poor Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>milies in the Countrey would be maintained, that now are in a ſtarving condition; Travellers would come into their Inns before Candlelight, ſtay in the morning till Shops open, underſtand the Trade of the place they are in, lay out monies in buying things they find fit for their uſe, and which are of the Manufactures of the Town where they come; in ſome places, Silk or Worſted-Hoſe; in others, Lace, Gloves, Stuffs, Boots, or Shoes, Linnen-Cloath, and other things, which would be great re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lief and encouragement to the Manufacturers of thoſe Commodities, as well as to thoſe that buy them, and bring money to thoſe places where they are made.</p>
               <pb n="38" facs="tcp:53444:21"/>
               <p n="4">4ly. Theſe Coaches are not abſolutely neceſſary to any perſons what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever; for ſick or aged people, or young children, if they have occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on to travel, may ride in the long Waggon-Coaches, which were thoſe that firſt were ſet up, and are not now oppoſed, becauſe they do little or no hurt: For, Gentlemen that are able to ride on horſeback, keep Coaches of their own, or to hire a Coach, will not appear ſo ſordid as to travel in them. And truly, if they be poor people that are to travel, it is not fit they ſhould be encouraged in their pride or extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vagancy, or ſuffered to ride amongſt Gentlemen, or like perſons of Honor in a Coach, with four or ſix horſes; and for ſick and aged people, and young children, theſe long Coaches are more convenient for them than running Coaches, if they were to be continued up; for, they travel not ſuch long journeys, go not out ſo early in the morning, neither come they in ſo late at night; but ſtay by the way, travel eaſily, without jolting mens bodies, or hurrying them along, as the running Coaches do.</p>
               <p n="5">5ly. Neither are theſe running Coaches uſeful to any, for, thoſe that are fit to ride, or ought to be ſuffered to ride in them, are ſuch, that if they have buſineſs requiring a Coach, may either keep one themſelves, or hire one.</p>
               <p n="6">6ly. But though theſe Coaches are neither abſolutely neceſſary to ſome, nor uſeful to others, yet they are impoſed upon many; for, ſince they ſet up in ſuch multitudes, eſpecially about <hi>London,</hi> men careleſs of keeping horſes, knowing the certainty of paſſage in them, have ſold them, and muſt therefore, when they travel, either ride in theſe Coaches, or not at all, there being few or no Horſes kept now to let out to hire.</p>
               <p>If by what hath been ſaid upon this point, it happen Gentlemen may travel on horſeback, more to the advantage and benefit of Trade, and ſo to the publick good, with more advantage to their healths and buſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, and leſs expence of money and time than they can in Stage-Coaches.</p>
               <p>If theſe Stage-Coaches be not abſolutely neceſſary to ſome, uſeful to what other Coaches may be made to others, and yet this impoſed upon many, what reaſon can be given why they ſhould not all or moſt of them be ſuppreſt?</p>
               <p>If they were not deſtructive to Trade, why ſhould Petitions from almoſt all ſorts of Tradeſmen, come up from moſt Cities and Towns in <hi>England</hi> againſt them, as there hath been lately preſented to His Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty and the Council? Why ſhould the Juſtices of Peace at their Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:53444:21"/>Quarter Seſſions, certifie to His Majeſtie and his honorable Privy Council, under their hands (as they have done) that the great Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chiefs aforementioned, under which the Kingdom now ſuffers, have been greatly occaſioned by theſe Coaches, and that many thouſands of Families are ruined by them, as from <hi>London, Weſtminſter, Salisbury, Middleſex,</hi> and divers other Cities, Counties and Towns, Certificates have come? Why ſhould the Lord Mayor and Aldermen of <hi>London,</hi> at their Court at <hi>Guildhal,</hi> upon ſerious conſideration and debate of the Petition of the ſeveral Companies of <hi>London,</hi> againſt the ſaid Coaches, wherein moſt of theſe grievances are mentioned, allow of the ſame, and give leave that it ſhould be preſented, if they were not convinced, that they are deſtructive to Trade? For ſurely they underſtand Trade, and were not ſo weak as to be cheated into their conſent and approba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion (neither have they any time ſince repented of, or diſowned the ſame) as the Stage-Coachmen in falſe and ſcandalous Pamphlets have preſumed to print; notwithſtanding which, they are ready to own the ſaid Petition, and make good the Contents thereof: And the <hi>Drapers, Haberdaſhers</hi> and <hi>Milliners,</hi> (who, they pretend, would be prejudiced by their being <hi>ſuperſeded</hi>) are ready, with the other Tradeſmen mention<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in that Pamphlet, to evince to the World, they are injured by their being kept up; ſo that the very Coach and Harneſs-Makers themſelves petition againſt them, as being miſchievous to their Trades, in regard they prevent the making of great Numbers of Coaches every year; which muſt have been made, if Gentlemen had travelled in their own Coaches, and thereby they hinder the Conſumption of great quantities of Leather.</p>
               <p>If all theſe things be true, what can be ſaid againſt their being ſuppreſt?</p>
               <p>It is Objected, <hi>The Owners of theſe Coaches ſet them up for the conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niency of the Subjects; have betaken themſelves to this painful way of living, and laid out their whole Stocks, meerly to accommodate Gentlemen, and have now no other way to live, what ſhall become of them, if they be put down?</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Anſ.</hi> It is the caſe but of very few, that the ſuppreſſing of them would hurt: for, if all Stage-Coaches were to be ſuppreſt, I dare ſay five for one of thoſe that keep them would receive advantage thereby, as clear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly will be evinced, if it be conſidered, that when this buſineſs was be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore His Majeſtie in Council, where it depends undetermined, none of the Stagers oppoſed the being put down, except <hi>Exeter, Salisbury, Dorcheſter, Briſtol, Southampton, Dover, Norwich, Lincoln, York, Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cheſter,
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:53444:22"/>Worceſter</hi> and <hi>Shrewsbury,</hi> who call themſelves, <hi>Stage-Coachmen upon the grand Roads of</hi> England; and there is not one Owner of any of theſe Coaches, but hath otherways to live, if he were prohibited driving them; for, they are all of them either Innholders, or Coach or Harneſs-makers, following thoſe Trades, or Carriers, or licenſed Coachmen in <hi>London;</hi> and may live as well as the Hackney Coachmen in <hi>London:</hi> The other Stage-Coaches, are all or moſt of them kept ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther by Innholders firſt, who (one in a Town) did ſet up a Coach, and ſo carried all the Gueſts to his own houſe. Then a ſecond ſets up another, and ſo a third and fourth in a Town: Which done, they run one againſt another, purpoſely to get the Gueſts from each other houſes; whereby they not only deſtroy multitudes of horſes, but are great loſers themſelves; ſo that themſelves would be thankful to have them put down, and yet are forced to keep them up, until there ſhall be a general ſuppreſſion, becauſe otherwiſe they ſhall loſe their whole Trades. Or elſe the ſaid Stage-Coaches are kept by ſuch, as before the late Act for re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ducing the number of Hackney Coaches in <hi>London</hi> to 400, were Owners of Coaches, and drove Hackney there: But when the number of 400 was full, and they not licenſed, then to avoid the penalties of the Act, they removed out of the City, diſperſing themſelves into every little Town within twenty miles of <hi>London,</hi> where they ſet up for Stagers, and Drive every Day to <hi>London,</hi> and in the night time they drive about the City, pay no 5 <hi>l. per annum,</hi> yet take away both the Town and Country work from thoſe that do pay it, and break and annoy the ſtreets in the Cities and Suburbs thereof, hinder the 400 from the Jobs and ſmall Journeys they depended upon, when they agreed to pay 5 <hi>l.</hi> a peice <hi>per annum</hi> for their Licences; whereby they are many of them ruined. But take it for granted it were ſo, that theſe Stage-Coachmen had laid out all their Stocks for the uſe aforeſaid, and muſt be undone if put down, and there were at leaſt 2000 of them, what is that? (of two evils the leſſer is to be choſen.) Have they not already deſtroyed very many Thouſands of Families? will not the continuing of them, in very ſhort time, be the undoing of many Thouſands more? is the intereſt of theſe ſnrley, rude, debauch'd Coachmen, to be put into the Ballance with the many Thouſands of <hi>Curriers, Shoemakers, Sadlers, Girdlers, Spurriers, Cutlers, Lorainers, Cloathiers, Cloath-workers, Cloath-drawers, Drapers, Taylors,</hi> and an hundred Trades more, to which men were bound ſeven years Apprentiſhip to learn their Trades, and are of great advantage to the publick. Surely, they ought to be encouraged, being the Manufacturers of the Staple-Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:53444:22"/>of the Kingdom; by the manufacturing whereof, great pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit doth ariſe to the Publick: Yet of theſe, if occaſion require, it will be made appear, above 100000, with their Families, are in great mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure ruined by them. And I pray you, who are advantaged thereby? what perſons are imployed or ſet at work by them, ſave only a few Servant-Coachmen, Poſtilions and Hoſtlers? whom they pretend they breed up and make fit for the ſervice of the Nobility and Gentry of the Land; a moſt incomparable School to train men up in! and to fit them for the Gallows, more likely than to live in ſober Families; but in the mean time, while theſe are breeding up, the Price and Rents of Lands are ſo brought down by hindrance theſe Coaches do make of the Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſumption of Proviſions and Manufactures, that in a ſhort time few Gentlemen will be in a capacity to keep Coaches; ſo that if all Run<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning Stage-Coaches and Caravans were ſuppreſt, it would do well. But if ſome few Coaches were continued, (to wit) one to every Shire-Town in <hi>England,</hi> to go once a week backwards and forwards, and to go through with the ſame Horſes they ſet forth with, and not travel above 30 miles a day in the Summer, and 25 miles in the Winter, and to ſhift Inns every Journey, that ſo Trade might be diffuſed; theſe would be ſufficient to carry the Sick and the Lame, that they pretend cannot tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vel on Horſeback<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and being thus regulated, they would do little or no harm; eſpecially if all be ſuppreſſed within 40 or 50 miles of <hi>London,</hi> where they are no way neceſſary, and yet ſo highly deſtructive. But this, as well as the reſt, I ſubmit to judgment.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <head>VIII.</head>
               <p>THe Eight Thing Propoſed is, That the Act for Tranſportation of Leather unmanufactured, may be repealed, or at leaſt not renew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed after the expiration thereof.</p>
               <p>There would never have been any neceſſity for this Act, had it not been that vaſt quantities of Hides are Iimported from <hi>Ireland,</hi> which brings down the price of our <hi>Engliſh</hi> Hides. And for the Stage-Coaches, their hindering the Conſumption of that Leather in <hi>England,</hi> which, before they ſet up, was uſed for Boots, Saddles, Portmantues, Hat-eaſes, Holſters, Belts, Girts, Reins, Stirrup Leathers, and ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny other things now, become almoſt uſeleſs.</p>
               <p>The making whereof, for Home-ſervice and Foreign-Conſumption,
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:53444:23"/>employed about 100000 Families, whoſe Livelihood depended upon the manufacturing of Leather, whereby they got Money, with which they maintained their Families, ſpent five or ſix good Joints of Meat in a week in their Houſes, and wore good Clothes, thereby occaſioning the Conſumption of great quantities of the Proviſions and Manufactures of the Kingdom, more than now are conſumed. Till this Act paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, it was felony to tranſport Leather unmanufactured, and then <hi>France, Spain, Germany,</hi> and other parts, who could not be without our Leather, had vaſt quantities of Boots, Shoes, and Saddles, with their Appurtenances, Portmantues, Hat-Caſes, Holſters, Trunks, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> from <hi>England;</hi> by the making whereof many thouſands of Families got a handſom ſubſiſtance, and grew rich; but Stage-Coaches hindring the Conſumption at home as aforeſaid; and <hi>Iriſh</hi> Hides being Imported into <hi>England,</hi> and alſo great quantities from <hi>Ireland,</hi> exported to Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reign Parts, our Hides fell in their price in <hi>England.</hi> The Queſtion then aroſe, how to raiſe them to their ancient value; and it was by the Parliament conceived, that giving a liberty to tranſport the ſame unmanufactured, might anſwer the end propoſed; therefore an Act for that purpoſe was paſſed.</p>
               <p>But ſad hath been, and yet is, the conſequence thereof: for, ever ſince that liberty given, the beſt of our Leather is conſtantly bought up, and tranſported beyond Seas unmanufactured, Foreigners who former<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly were ſupplyed with Leather wrought here, will not buy or carry over a penny-worth that is manufactured; ſo that all thoſe poor peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple who ſerved Apprentiſhips to learn their Trades, and whoſe Trade depended upon manufacturing for Foreign Conſumption, are undone; they that kept 20 or 30 Journey-men at work every day, cannot now (though eminent men of their own Trades) keep two; by means whereof, upon computation, at leaſt 50000 Men and their Families Livelyhoods are wholly taken away, and they ſo impoveriſhed, that they are ready to receive Alms of the ſeveral pariſhes wherein they live; whilſt in the mean time Foreigners grow rich by manufacturing one of the Staple Commodities of this Kingdom; and whereas till this Act paſſed, all our old Boots and Shoes were bought up, mended here, and then ſent beyond the Seas, and there worn.</p>
               <p>The caſe is now otherwiſe; for the beſt of our Leather is not onely bought up and tranſported unmanufactured and wrought beyond Seas; but when it is wrought, it is then imported back, and vended here, to the great prejudice and diſcouragement of Manufacturers in <hi>England,</hi> who have many of them been forced (as great a want of
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:53444:23"/>People as there is in <hi>England</hi>) to tranſport themſelves beyond the Seas for want of work at home, and there have taught their Art to Foreig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners. What then doth naturally follow all theſe things? What Conſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quence can be drawn from hence, but this, that inſtead of 500 <hi>ls.</hi> worth of Leather formerly ſent beyond Seas manufactured, we ſend now as much Leather, but it is not worth above 100 <hi>l.</hi> becauſe the ſame is car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ried over unwrought: by which means our Manufacturers loſe 400 <hi>l.</hi> which they ſhould have gotten, if the Leather had been Cut and Wrought in <hi>England,</hi> and ſo thereby we grow poor; and Foreigners grow rich, by gaining that 400 <hi>l.</hi> which our Manufacturers loſe.</p>
               <p>But this is not all; for, moſt of our Leather that is exported, goes into <hi>France,</hi> with whom we never were able to keep up a Ballance of Trade, but have traded with them for ready Money, (they taking little or none of the Manufactures of <hi>England</hi> in exchange for their Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modities). By a moderate computation, from the beſt intelligence I can get, <hi>France</hi> receives from <hi>England</hi> 30000 <hi>ls.</hi> worth of our Leather every year, which they cannot be without (for, our Leather-Manufa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cture, was the only Manufacture that they were forced to be holden un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to us for). 30000 <hi>ls.</hi> worth of our Leather manufactured, was worth in <hi>France</hi> 120000 <hi>l.</hi> then at leaſt 70000 <hi>l.</hi> of that went into our Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>facturers Pockets, the reſt to the Merchants, and what our Manufuctu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers got, was ſpent in the Proviſions and Manufactures of the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom; which being conſumed, bare a better rate than now, and helpt to keep up the Rents of Lands.</p>
               <p>This Money we not only now loſe, to our Impoveriſhment, and the <hi>French</hi> get, to their Inriching; but conſidering that we now import as much (nay far more) of <hi>French</hi> Goods into <hi>England</hi> than we did for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merly; and taking it for granted, that when we tranſported the moſt that ever we did, yet could not a ballance of Trade be kept up between the two Kingdoms, but our ready Money went for a great part of the Goods imported; then muſt it naturally follow, that by ſending our Leather unmanufactured, which formerly was mannfactured, we muſt ſend over nigh 100000 <hi>l.</hi> more in ready Money than formerly we did, (or need to do were it not for this Act) which furniſheth <hi>France</hi> with our Coyn, to pay their Workmen for manufacturing of our Staple-Commodities, and greatly exhauſteth the Treaſure of this Kingdom; But if this Act be repealed, and <hi>Irelands</hi> tranſporting of Raw Hides be prevented, then <hi>France</hi> and other Foreigners muſt have Leather from <hi>England</hi> manufactured, as formerly they had, whereby our Handicraft Tradeſmen would be ſet at work, and having work, would live hand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſomely
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:53444:24"/>as formerly they did, to conſume the Proviſions and Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factures of the Kingdom: So that to any rational man it muſt be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parent, that this Act hath not anſwered the end deſigned, nor raiſed the price of Hides, as expected, nor can it: for <hi>Ireland</hi> tranſporting vaſt quantities of raw Hides beyond the Seas, and Importing great quantities of their Hides into <hi>England,</hi> as aforeſaid, hinders the ſale of our Hides or Tanned Leather at any: conſiderable rates, either at home, or to Foreigners, becauſe we want a Conſumption at home; and Foreigners chuſe to buy their raw Hides rather than our Leather, by reaſon they can purchaſe them at a third part of the price we can afford to ſell ours at, and by tanning of them employ their own Bark; which is a great miſchief to the Gentry in <hi>England,</hi> whoſe Bark, by reaſon thereof, ſells at very low rates.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <head>IX.</head>
               <p>THe Ninth thing propoſed is, That a Court in the nature of a Court of Requeſts in <hi>London,</hi> be eſtabliſhed for <hi>Weſtminſter, Southwark,</hi> and all other parts within the Weekly Bills of Mortality; and, if poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible, in every City and Town Corporate in <hi>England,</hi> to determine Dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferences between poor people for ſmall Debts, not exceeding 40 <hi>s.</hi> and for Words, Treſpaſſes, Aſſaults and Batteries (where the people pay neither Scot nor Lot) that ſo they may not be undone by Law-ſuits.</p>
               <p>The Court of Requeſts in <hi>London</hi> is of excellent uſe, long continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance, and hath prevented the ruine of many thouſands of Families, and might have done far more, had it not been limitted to the Liberties of the City; whereby all <hi>Weſtminſter, Southwark, Tower-Hamlets, Middle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſex</hi> and <hi>Surry,</hi> within the Weekly Bills of Mortalities, wherein the ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerality of the poor inhabit, are excluded their Juriſdiction.</p>
               <p>Of theſe Poor (for want of this Court) many are every year undone by Law-Suits, commenced againſt each other for ſmall debts, or trivi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al Actions, for Words, Aſſaults, or Treſpaſſes, the pooreſt oftentimes proving the proudeſt, moſt quarrelſome and vexatious.</p>
               <p>Theſe are ſuch who maintain themſelves and Families, by turning and winding 20 or 40 <hi>s.</hi> a week, which they take upon their credit, and employ in buying and ſelling Butchers-meat, Poultery-ware, and Fiſh, Herbs, Fruit and Roots, Boiled-Wheat and Oat-cakes, Butter and Eggs, and divers other things, which they cry about the ſtreets, or ſell at Tavern-doors, or in little Bulks, as Orenges, Limons, Oyſters,
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:53444:24"/>Tape, Thred-laces, Silk and Ferret Ribbon, Childrens Play-things, and ſuch like ſmall Commodities, whereby they keep their Families from burthening they Pariſhes wherein they dwell; and yet are ſo poor, that they are not rated to the Church and Poor where they trade.</p>
               <p>Theſe people are (the greateſt part of them) moſt commonly in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>debted 20, 30. or 40 <hi>s.</hi> apiece for the Stock they trade with; never<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>theleſs have more owing to them, by the perſons they ſell their Wares to, than when received will pay ſuch their Debts; but there are cun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning Fellows belonging to the <hi>Marſhalſey,</hi> St. <hi>Katherines, Whitechappel</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> (pretending to be Baillffs or other Officers) placed in every part of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and the Suburbs thereof, who make it their buſineſs to enquire out theſe Poor and their Creditors, and thereupon to contrive ſome ſtories whereby to incite their Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors to make a demand of their Debts; and if not preſently paid, then to arreſt the Debtors: Theſe Knaves alſo ſpend their whole time in promoting differences between the poorer ſort of people, for frivolous words, ſlight treſpaſſes, or pitiful ſmall debts; which done, they are imployed to arreſt men; and the perſon arreſted, muſt either preſently pay and give ſatisfaction, or put in Bail; the which if he cannot do (as frequently it happens they cannot, they laying their Actions high (though the occaſion of action be very ſmall) then they are hurried over to the Knight Marſhals Priſon, or to ſome other Goal, and put to great expence, loſe their Credit and Trade, and very many of them are ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terly ruined by the charge of Arreſts, Priſon Fees, and the Suits, though the verdict upon their Tryals happen to be for them, as moſt commonly it is, there being not one Action in ten brought in thoſe Courts for Words or Treſpaſſes, that happens to be according to Law.</p>
               <p>Nevertheleſs, if the ſaid Defendants Demur, becauſe the words are not actionable, or the Plaintiff have a Verdict, and the Defendant move in Arreſt of Judgement, and the Judgement be Arreſted, yet in neither of theſe Caſes hath the Defendant any Coſts; ſo that both Plaintiffs and Defendants ſpend their money in vain; and the Pariſhes where the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendants inhabit, are frequently forced to redeem them out of the Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhalſeys, <hi>White Chappel,</hi> St. <hi>Katharines,</hi> and other Goals, or otherwiſe they ſhould lie and ſtarve in Priſon, though the Cauſe of Action were but a Trifle; the Charges and Fees oftentimes falling out to be four, five or ſix times as much as originally the Action was brought for; by reaſon whereof the recovering of 4 <hi>d.</hi> 6 <hi>d.</hi> or 12 <hi>d.</hi> ſometimes coſts 3 <hi>l.</hi> 4 <hi>l.</hi> or 6 <hi>l.</hi> Whereas if the Court deſired were erected to end theſe Differences in a ſummary, leſs expenſive, and more expeditious
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:53444:25"/>way, the utter ruine of ſome hundreds, if not thouſands of Families, would be every year prevented, the Pariſh charges greatly leſſened, and quarrelſome vexatious Suits for ſmall Debts of 40 <hi>s.</hi> or under, or for Treſpaſſes, Aſſaults, or words, would be prevented.</p>
               <p>In <hi>London,</hi> no Freeman within the Liberties dwelling, can be arreſted or ſued for any Debt under Forty ſhillings; the <hi>Court of Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcience</hi> or <hi>Requeſts</hi> ſits at <hi>Guildhal Wedneſday</hi> and <hi>Saturdays</hi> in every week, to hear Complaints, and take courſe therein: Upon any Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint they firſt ſend a Summons to the party complained againſt, and that is ſerved upon him by a ſworn Officer, and coſts 6 <hi>d.</hi> which done, the next Court day the Plaintiff muſt attend, and call the Defendant, and enter his own appearance; elſe is non-ſuited, loſeth his Summons, and muſt begin again; but the Defendant runs no hazard in not ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pearing the firſt day.</p>
               <p>If the Defendant appear the ſecond Court day after Summons, he prevents an Attachment, and is ordered to pay his debt; for which the Plaintiff pays 4 <hi>d.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>If the Defendant fail to appear the ſecond Court day, before the Court riſeth, the Court grants an Attachment; which coſts, being ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecuted, amount to 1 <hi>s.</hi> 10 <hi>d.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Officer ſerves this Attachment, ſo ſoon as he can find the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant; which done, he gives the Plaintiff notice, that the Defendant will meet him next Court day, and that coſts 4 <hi>d.</hi> more.</p>
               <p>If the Defendant appear, and is caſt, he pays for the Summons and Attachment; which is but 2 <hi>s.</hi> eight pence in the whole.</p>
               <p>But if the Defendannt appear not the third Court day after Attach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, than the Plaintiff comes and ſwears his Debt, and the Court or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders payment thereof at the Plaintiffs own houſe, if he pleaſeth; which ſaves 8 <hi>d.</hi> that muſt be paid, if it be brought into Court, to take it out again, and this Order coſts 4 <hi>d.</hi> more.</p>
               <p>Of this Order the Officer gives the Defendant notice, and that he muſt meet the Plaintiff in Court the third Court day after the making thereof.</p>
               <p>If the Defendant appear not the third Court day, then upon the Plaintiffs requeſt, the Courts grants Judgment and Execution againſt him; which coſts 2 <hi>s.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>So that the whole Charge of Summons, Order and Attachment;</p>
               <p>Second Order for Judgement, and the Judgement and Execution executed, comes but to 4 <hi>s.</hi> 8 <hi>d.</hi>
               </p>
               <pb n="47" facs="tcp:53444:25"/>
               <p>And all is done in three weeks time: but the Suit in the <hi>Marſhalſey, White Chappel,</hi> or St. <hi>Katherines,</hi> or <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> Courts, and Charges in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cident thereunto, coſts 4 <hi>l.</hi> or 5 <hi>l.</hi> when the Debt or Cauſe of Action was not worth Five ſhillings.</p>
               <p>The erecting the Court deſired, would give a great credit to the Poor.</p>
               <p>For, were ſuch Courts erected, every Gentleman or perſon of any conſiderable eſtate would lend a poor diſtreſſed neighbour Twenty, Thirty, or Forty ſhillings, to put him in a way to live, or to prevent their being caſt into Priſon, if arreſted for a ſmall ſum; whereas now poor men are forced to borrow of Brokers, pawn double the value of what they borrow, and pay above <hi>Cent. per Cent.</hi> intereſt; which eats out their profit, ſo preſſeth and grindes them, that they frequently are incapacitated to redeem the Pledges left for the money taken up (which is one other great miſchief worthy the conſideration of the Parliament, and fit to be redreſſed) whereas whilſt the Law is thus coſtly, men are afraid to lend their Neighbours Thirty or Forty ſhillings to ſet them up with, or to prevent their being impriſoned, becauſe if they repay it not without a Suit, the ſame may coſt five or ſix times as much as the Original Debt; and when the Creditor hath Judgement, he is not ſure of his Debt, but in danger, through the poverty of the Creditor, to loſe both Principal, Debt, Intereſt and Charges, or undergo the hard Cenſures and Clamours of the poor, by confining them to Priſon; which no ingenuous or generous ſoul can endure the thoughts of.</p>
               <p>By the erecting this Court, there is none can be prejudiced, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepting,</p>
               <list>
                  <item>Firſt, <hi>Bailiffs,</hi> one of which fellows to arreſt a poor man, though it be but for three pence, four pence, or ſome other very ſmall ſum, makes the man pay four or five ſhillings for the Arreſt, hurries him into an Alehouſe, and there runs him twelve pence or two ſhillings on the ſcore; and if not able preſently to pay the ſame, hurries him to Priſon.</item>
                  <item>Secondly, Several idle Perſons, falſly calling themſelves <hi>Attorneys,</hi> who are as active as the Bayliffs, to promote and carry on Suits be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gun, though but for trivial Matters, ſetting people together by the ears, and living upon the ruine of the poor, make them ſell their very Beds from under them, or Cloaths from off their backs, to pay their pretended Fees, and the Fees of the Courts, which is too frequently done.</item>
                  <pb n="48" facs="tcp:53444:26"/>
                  <item>Thirdly, Or the Judges of the <hi>Marſhalſey, Weſtminſter,</hi> St. <hi>Katha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rines, White-Chappel,</hi> and other Inferior Courts of Record, where ſmall Debts under 40 <hi>s.</hi> may be recovered: but certainly, they having their places given them <hi>gratis,</hi> and being perſons of generous educati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, will not oppoſe ſo charitable a work as this propoſed, though they ſhould loſe ſome profit thereby, ſuch profit coming from ſuch miſerable poor people, that it were charity in them rather to give them as much as their Fees comes to, than to exact any thing from them.</item>
               </list>
               <p>And if they, by the Court deſired, ſhould loſe a little profit, they will ſave much time that they now ſpend in trying theſe Cauſes, and being Lawyers, may certainly ſpend it to as great (if not better) advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage than what they will loſe by ſetting up the Judicature propoſed.</p>
               <p>Let theſe conſider, that ſuch Gentlemen, not being Lawyers, as ſhall be appointed Judges of the Courts deſired, will be greater loſers than they are, ſince they muſt ſit and ſpend their Time and Money with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out any manner of Compenſation at all, ſave the ſatisfaction they will receive in being inſtrumental of doing good to the Poor, which cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tainly they will do.</p>
               <p>For whereas now it coſts 5 or 6 <hi>l.</hi> to recover 5 or 6 <hi>s.</hi> by the way propoſed, 4 <hi>s.</hi> 8 <hi>d.</hi> is all the Charge (though the Suits be ſpun out to the utmoſt extremity) that any Suitor or Defendant can be put unto.</p>
               <p>So by the ſetting up of this Court, Juſtice will be had ſpeedier and cheaper;</p>
               <p>The ruine of many poor People, by multitudes of vexatious Suits for ſmall Matters, will be prevented;</p>
               <p>Love and Amity betwixt Neighbours will be preſerved; Charges of the Pariſhes leſſened; Mens Liberties to follow their Callings, to their own and Families Comfort, will be continued; and the Debts they owe, be more eaſily and ſpeedily payed;</p>
               <p>And a Work very pleaſing and acceptable to God will be done, who hath pronounced a bleſſing upon all thoſe who conſider the Poor, for whoſe relief alone this is propoſed.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <pb n="49" facs="tcp:53444:26"/>
               <head>X.</head>
               <p>THe Tenth Thing Propoſed is, That a bound be put to the extra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vagant Habits and Expences of all ſorts of Perſons; that Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants and Handicraft Tradeſmen's expenſive wayes be reduced, and no Foreign Manufactures (except from <hi>Ireland</hi>) be ſuffered to be worn in <hi>England;</hi> but that the Importation and Expoſing them to Sale, be made Felony.</p>
               <p>There is nothing ruines the Gentry and Tradeſmen of <hi>England</hi> ſo much, as living above their Eſtates or Profit ariſing by their Trades. How much all ſorts of men do this, I leave the World to judge, their Habits and other Expences being more extravagant and vain than ever was known; and not only do Maſters and Miſtreſſes of Families run to exceſs in their own dreſſes, but ſuffer and encourage their Servants alſo to do the ſame, which coſts them dear at laſt; for, all comes out of their Pockets, and it makes Servants ſo proud and ſcornful, as to ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>glect their Duties, ſlight their Superiors, and upon every little reproof to go from them.</p>
               <p>How many Gentlemen are there in <hi>England</hi> that ſpend their whole yearly Incomes upon clothing themſelves, their Wives and Children? What way then have they to anſwer their other Familie Expences, but by ſpending upon the main Stock?</p>
               <p>How careleſs are Parents of their Childrens Education, bringing them up idly, putting them upon no manner of imployment, unleſs to Muſick and Dancing; uſing them to Balls and Playes, and to keep vain Company; which they get ſuch an habit of, that they very hardly (if ever) can be broken from it, but ſpend-moſt of their time in Gaming, Whoring, and Drinking; ſo that by that time they come to their Eſtates, whatever their Fathers leave them, by following their Exam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples, they quickly make it away, (if they have not run it out before they come to it). Their Clothes muſt be of the Mode, Gentlemen of 3 or 400 <hi>per annum,</hi> will be as fine, keep their Coaches, live as high as if they were Lords, and had great Eſtates; and nothing will ſerve them but what is Foreign made, whilſt our own Countrey-men ſtarve for want of Work; inſomuch now that our <hi>Engliſh</hi> Manufacturers, of Silk eſpecially, and Point-Laces, and Ribbons, (which are become a general wear) cannot ſell their Goods when they have made them; or if
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:53444:27"/>they do, it is at ſuch pittiful low rates, that they loſe by their work, and the Shopkeepers that buy them, when they come to ſhew them to Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomers, are forced to avouch them to be Foreign made, or elſe they cannot ſell them; ſo that our Manufacturers are often neceſſitated to get <hi>French</hi>-men to go with their Wares, and ſell them to Shopkeepers as <hi>French.</hi> Thereupon the Gentry (though the Goods be <hi>Engliſh</hi> made) are ſo fond as to pay dearer for them than otherwiſe they need to do, becauſe of the Brokage which the Manufacturer payes to thoſe that ſell them to the Shops, and ſo the Manufacturers get little or no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing by them. So great a truth there is in this, that I could inſtance where Perſons of Quality have come into a Shop, ſeen a Commodity, liked it well, but being ingeniouſly told that it was <hi>Engliſh</hi> made, would not buy it. The very next day, the ſame Goods have been ſent by a <hi>French</hi> woman to the Perſons deſiring to buy the ſame, and they have bought them as <hi>French</hi> Goods, and payed double as much for them as they might have had them for the day before in the Shop.</p>
               <p>Is not this a thing highly commendable in our Gentry, ſo to admire Foreigners, and undervalue, diſcourage, and hurt their Native Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trey-men? Did they conſider, or were they but ſenſible how they hurt and ruine them, themſelves, and their own Eſtates, by ſuch their vain fancies, hindring the Conſumption of our Manufacturies, and impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veriſhing our Manufacturers, certainly they would give it over. A further miſchief there is alſo, That Gentlemen and Ladies do fancy greatly to have their Servants that are about them, ſo fine and neat, that they muſt be in their Silk-Gowns, and Peticoats laced, Whisks, and Cuffs, fine Shoes and Stockings, that they will not do any ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Work; whereby they are neceſſitated to keep more Servants than they uſed or need to do. And what the Wages and Dyet of every Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vant comes to in a year, (eſpecially about <hi>London,</hi> where it is that moſt people are grown ſo vain) let themſelves compute.</p>
               <p>Come to the Citizens, who complain for want of a Trade, but with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out a Cauſe, (though ſo many Tradeſmen fail yearly) for there never was a greater Trade than there is now. What reaſon is there then of their failing? It is high living, every Tradeſman thinking now to have as great a Trade, and as quickly to grow rich, as thoſe did that were of his Trade twenty or thirty years agoe, never conſidering that there are five times as many of moſt Trades as were then, and that thereby Trade is more diffuſed, Shopkeepers of late years, through covetouſneſs of a little Money, taking double or treble the number of Apprentices that formerly they kept, or indeed (if ſtrictly looked after) than they ought to
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:53444:27"/>keep, (nothing ſpoyling any particular Trade, more than to have mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiplicy of Traders in the ſame way); with theſe Apprentices they ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>act as much more money as formerly they uſed to have, ſo that per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps half their Portion is gone to bind them Apprentices; which is a great madneſs, and no reaſon to be given for it, but becauſe Apprenti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces muſt live high, and wear finer Cloaths than formerly they did, wait on their Maſters abroad, do none of the ſervile Work that formerly they uſed to do; which kept them humble; and if they were now obliged to the ſame, it would keep them from growing ſo proud and ſcorn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful as they are, or taking the liberty they now do, of taunting at their Superiors, quarrelling with their Services, Uſage, and Diet, and go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing from them, when fit to do them ſervice; And if it happen that they do ſerve out their Time, and have a 1000 <hi>l.</hi> to ſet up with, it is very well, and a fair beginning, treble as much as many of their Maſters had when they ſet up; who by cloſe living, and diligence, and great induſtry, after many years care and pains, have arrived to an Eſtate of 30, 30, or 40000 <hi>l.</hi> and a good certain cuſtom, ſo conſequently are able to buy their Commodities with ready Money, cheaper than he that hath but a ſmall ſtock, and trades upon credit, and thereby they are able to keep the cuſtom from their Servants when they ſet up, becauſe they can give Cuſtomers a greater credit, and a longer time for pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; yet a young Man, ſo ſoon as he comes out of his Time, not knowing whether ever he ſhall attain to a full Trade, will have as good a Houſe as his Maſters keep, as high a Table, lay out 4. or 500 <hi>l.</hi> out of his 1000 <hi>l.</hi> Stock, in furniſhing his Houſe, and the Fine of the ſame; his deſign being thereby to advance himſelf in a Match. And thereupon he gets a Wife, perhaps with a 1000 <hi>l.</hi> Portion; which, ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded to his own Stock, if the ſame had been kept together, would have made 2000 <hi>l.</hi> but of this, one half of his being gone for a Fine of a Houſe and Furniture, as aforeſaid, the Wife, out of Hers, will have fine Cloaths, Laces, Cupboards of Plate, Neck-Lace of Pearls, Jewels in her Ears, Diamond-Rings on her Fingers, Bulls-Locks, or Towers; Laced or Imbroidered Petticoats, Shoes and Silk-Hoſe. So that in theſe Things goes 3 or 400 <hi>l.</hi> more, which might, moſt of it, have been ſaved.</p>
               <p>Add to this the vaſt Rent he ſits at, and muſt pay whether he hath a Trade or not; If this had been ſpared, he might have had it of his own to have traded with: but this laid out, it lyes dead, whilſt he is forced for want thereof, to Trade upon Credit for ſo much, and pay Intereſt for the ſame. This Credit if he keeps not, he is loſt; and being ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſitated to truſt, and truſting being dangerous, many men are undone;
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:53444:28"/>partly by that, and partly by the extravagancies of their good Wives; who being, through their Husbands vanity and indiſcretion, made ſo fine, will not ſtir out of Doors without a Coach; and yet make ſuch frequent and long viſits, that they ſpend more in Coach-hire ſome weeks, than the gains of the Shop comes to; and abroad they get new Acquaintance, at Balls, Playes, or Dancing-Schools; and being young, pretty, and in fine Cloaths, are ſo courted and gallanted, that oftentimes they are perſwaded into ſuch Inconveniencies, as prove fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tal to their Husbands, as well as to themſelves; but the Husbands may blame themſelves, they being originally the occaſion thereof, and o their own ruine thereby; for, nothing will ſerve them but to live at this rate, keep their Wives thus fine, expoſe them to Temptations, by ſetting them in their Shops, in tempting Dreſſes, thinking to invite Cuſtomers; and thereby very often they have that effect; but ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times thoſe Cuſtomers make bold with the Ware that ſhould not be ſold or lent; and once having attained that liberty, if both Parries agree, it is ten to one if that poor Man be not preſently blown up, either by the charge his Wife will put him to in maintaining that Gallant, or by the Credit that good Gentleman ſhall have in the Shop, to take up what he pleaſes. And then when gone as far as the Owner can give credit for, he leaves the Shop and his Miſtreſs to his care. Nevertheleſs, ſometimes men are undone, and yet their Wives are vertuous, (as without doubt many thouſands are, and more would be, were it not the Husbands fault); That is, when after their being a while ſet up, and a little E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate gotten, they grow high, keep their Coaches, muſt have their Countrey-Houſes, the Candles burning at both ends, never thinking they ſhall ſee an end of their Gains. And their Wives forſooth muſt not be Nurſes, but ſend their Children abroad; ſo that reckoning the charge of keeping there, and frequent going to ſee them, and the Guifts and good things that are unknown carried to the Nurſes; theſe high Expences, accompanied with a decay and declination of Trade, occaſioned by the multiplicity of Traders, (as aforeſaid) go far in de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroying young Beginners. Moreover, the keeping unneceſſary Maid-Servants, giving them great Wages, and maintaining them idle in fine Habits and Dreſſes, (who with their vain and wanton carriages, often<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>times become ſnares to young men); this finiſheth the work, and both Maſters, Miſtreſſes, and Servants, come all to ruine thereby.</p>
               <p>One other great miſchief to the young Tradeſmen, who are induſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous, cloſe husbands, and ſober in their habits and expences, is the great Rents they in the City, when the Trade is gone to the other end of
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:53444:28"/>the Town where Rents are low. Were all men of my mind, thoſe who lived in <hi>London</hi> before the fire, and are Freemen, and now, to the deſtruction of the City, live in the Suburbs, meerly to enrich them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, they ſhould ſtarve before a peny ſhould be laid out amongſt them: Why ſhould they not come into the City again, and make that the ſeat of Trade? which is the Metropolitan of <hi>England,</hi> and at ſuch vaſt charge, in Complyance with the Kings pleaſure, is nobly rebuilt, and ſo many thouſands are undone by the building thereof, by having their houſes ſtand empty on their hands; ſuch baſe treacherous men to the City, who no more value their Oaths they took when bound Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentices and made free, ought not to be countenanced where they are, by buying any thing of them; there is not one of them but is forſworn, if he duly weigh and conſider the purport of his Oath. And he that will make no Conſcience of forſwearing himſelf, meerly to gain a little advantage in his Trade, I am ſure will make no Conſcience of cheat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of me; therefore ſhall never have any of my cuſtom.</p>
               <p>One other great miſchief to young Tradeſmen is, that they, being but beginners, are forced to keep Shops, in order to gain a cuſtom, and thereby are conſtrained to pay great Rents and Taxes, which are very hard upon <hi>London,</hi> treeble as much in proportion, as upon any one County of <hi>England,</hi> and paid by theſe young men, whilſt your cunning rich ancient Tradeſmen, having a large Acquaintance, great Stock, and a full Trade, give over their Shops, and take a Country-houſe, where they live for a ſmall Rent, pay not the ſixth part of Taxes that are paid in <hi>London,</hi> and ſo carry on their Trade in <hi>London</hi> privately in Warehouſes. I could name ſeveral of the Chief Magiſtrates that do ſo, but will not at preſent, though they deſerve it. Have they, through Gods bleſſing, arrived by their Trades in the City to great Eſtates, and to be the chief Magiſtrates thereof, only to be covetous and ſordid, ſeek<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to ſave a little money, when they have ſo much that they know not what to do with it, and thereby put all the Charges upon thoſe young Shop-keepers, through their Avarice? And thus many of theſe young men fall to ruine, whilſt the elder run away with all the Trade, and Engroſs the ſame into their own hands. It is a great ſhame this ſhould be ſuffered, and ſuch men ought not to have any manner of Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment or Power in or over the City, who make uſe of it only to enrich themſelves, by deſtroying thoſe they govern.</p>
               <pb n="54" facs="tcp:53444:29"/>
               <p>Moreover, Handicraft Tradeſmens high wages, which they exact for their work, is greatly miſchievous, not only to every man that hath occaſion to uſe them, whoſe particular occaſion cannot be ſerved but at far greater rates than formerly, which, if that were all, would be little, but it is deſtructive to Trade, hinders the conſumption of our Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factures by Foreigners, and the exportation of thoſe vaſt quantities that uſed to be tranſported, when the manufacturing of them was ſo cheap as formerly; for, now Wool and Leather being cheaper manufactured beyond the Seas than here, we are underſold in Foreign Markets, to our great prejudice; which if not prevented, in few years will tend to the total ruine and deſtruction of our Woollen and Leather Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>facturies. I can give no better account for this advancement of their wages, than our <hi>Engliſh</hi> peoples fooliſhneſs, in encouraging Foreigners beyond their own Neighbours, wearing their Manufacturies, and neg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lecting the uſe of our own; by means whereof our Manufacturers work is carried away from them: ſo that whereas they had ſix days work formerly, they have not above three now, and having the ſame families, muſt either have double the wages they had when they had full Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ploy (which enhaunceth the price of the Commodities) or let their fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>milies want bread three days in the week.</p>
               <p>So the Caſe thus ſtands in ſhort: As for the loſs of the Foreign Trade we had, and the want of the conſumption that uſed to be of our Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nufacturies in Foreign parts, no other reaſon can be given, but that Foreigners are able to make their work cheaper than we do, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by are able to underſel us where-ever we come; and the reaſon of their working cheaper is, becauſe they live not ſo high, neither are their ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pences in wages and working ſo great as ours. If they were, how could Foreigners fetch our Wool and Leaher, pay Freight and Cuſtom outward, manufacture it abroad, and then Import it back again, paying a ſecond Cuſtom, and yet ſell it cheaper here than we do ours? If this be true, and thereby the Foreign Conſumption of our Manufacturies be loſt, the more reaſon there is then, in my poor judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, to endeavour the reducing the wages of our Manufacturers, and themſelves to a more ſober, and leſs expenſive way of living, that there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by, if poſſible, we may regain that Trade: Which if we do, we ſhall ſoon ſet our people at work (who now want bread.) And nothing can be more conducing to this end, than to enjoyn all <hi>Engliſh</hi> men not to wear any thing but what is of our own Growth and Manufacturies; which will encreaſe a Conſumption at home, and ſet thoſe at work who now live idle, and by giving them full work, would bring down
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:53444:29"/>their wages: ſo that then we having our Wool and Leather cheaper than Foreiguers have, and being able to manufacture them at as eaſie rates as they do, it will then neceſſarily follow, that we may underſel them in Foreign Markets; which if we can do, and will be honeſt, make good ſubſtantial and true work, that will hold out its weight, and the full length and breadth they formerly did, we may regain that Foreign Trade.</p>
               <p>And the better to effect this, all Foreign Manufacturies (except of Linnen, which we cannot be without) ought to be prohibited, and the expoſing them to ſale made Felony (ſo as the perſon ſelling be privy to their being ſuch) except what is manufactured in <hi>Ireland;</hi> which of neceſſity we muſt make our ſelves Maſters of, otherwiſe they having Wool, and Leather, and Workmen cheaper then we can have, will by ſupplying Foreign Markets at Lower rates than we can ſell for, gain that Trade; and thereby deſtroy ours. But if theſe be imported into <hi>England,</hi> and bought by us, though we buy them cheap, yet when we have them, we may hold up and advance their price, ſo as to make them bear equal proportion with what we can afford our own for; (which we may do alſo with their Cattel if Imported again) and being Maſters both of their and our own, enforce Foreigners (eſpeci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally if the Exportation of Wool and Leather be prevented) to be be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holding to us for what they want, and can no where elſe have; where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by Trade will be encreaſed, Conſumption of the Products of our Lands promoted, and thereby the price of them will be raiſed, and conſequently Lands yield better Rents: And by this encreaſe of Trade, His Majeſties Revenue by a moderate Computation, would be advanced above One hundred thouſand pounds <hi>per annum;</hi> which would be an additional help towards payment of the Publick Debts, and no preju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dice, but a great advantage to his Majeſties Subjects.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <pb n="56" facs="tcp:53444:30"/>
               <head>XI.</head>
               <p>THe Eleventh Propoſal is, That it may be lawful for any man to aſſign Bills, Bonds, or other Securities, to any perſon, or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons whatſoever; and that by virtue of ſuch Aſſignment, the Intereſt in the ſaid Debt due upon ſuch Security, may immediately be veſted in the Aſſignee. And to the end that the frauds by falſe Entries in Shop-Books may be prevented. That it be made unlawful for any perſon after three years to ſue for a Book-Debt, and that the great Deceits uſed by many perſons, who break meerly to deceive Creditors, may (if poſſible) by ſome ſevere and ſtrict Law be prevented: Than which,</p>
               <list>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Firſt,</hi> There is hardly any thing can be of greater advantage to Trade.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Secondly,</hi> Of greater ſecurity to the Gentry; that they ſhall not for the future be wronged.</item>
                  <item>
                     <hi>Thirdly,</hi> Of more advantage to the Nation in general.</item>
               </list>
               <p>For want of power to aſſign Securities, many Tradeſmen and Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen are every year undone.</p>
               <p>It is true, that men commonly make Letters of Attorney to their Creditors, to enable them to put Bonds, Bills, or other Securities, into ſuit, that are made to them; but thoſe Letters of Attorney are re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vokeable; ſo that the men to whom they are made, are not ſecure, that the perſon that makes them, ſhall not afterwards revoke the ſame, or diſcharge any Suit brought upon any ſuch Bill, Bond, or other Secu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity, by virtue of ſuch Letters of Attorney: and ſo no man will ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept of any Bond entred into to another man, and a Letter of Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney from the perſon to whom the ſame is entred into, as a Security for any debt due to himſelf from the perſon to whom ſuch Bond is given. Tradeſmen live upon Credit, buy much upon Truſt, are obliged to pay on certain days; on which if they fail, their Credit is loſt; and as they buy upon Credit, ſo they muſt ſell upon Truſt: And if the perſon truſted by them, pay not at the time limited, yet are they that truſt them obliged to obſerve punctually their days of payment, becauſe the Credit of thoſe Merchants that truſt them, depends thereupon. Nevertheleſs, many Tradeſmen, becauſe they cannot get in what is owing to them, are enforced to fail in point of their payments, which
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:53444:30"/>leſſens their Credit, begets Suits; and thoſe Suits occaſion the ruine of many Families, although the perſons ſued have in other mens hands good Debts, which, when received, would be ſufficient to anſwer all their Creditors.</p>
               <p>But if the Aſſignment of Debts due upon Bill, Bond, or other Secu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rities, were, by Act of Parliament, made lawful, and it were Enacted, that ſuch Aſſignments ſhould be irrevocable; and that the Intereſt in the Debts due upon ſuch Security, ſhould by virtue of ſuch Aſſign<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, be actually veſted in the Aſſignee, then if <hi>A.</hi> owed <hi>B.</hi> the Sum of 500 <hi>l.</hi> and <hi>B.</hi> owed <hi>C.</hi> 500 <hi>l.</hi> his time of payment were come, and he had no Moneys to pay the ſame, the Aſſignment of <hi>A.</hi> his Bond to <hi>C.</hi> would be accepted, if he were a perſon anſwerable, in diſcharge of <hi>B.</hi> his Debt. And if he had occaſion to pay Money, and had it not by him, <hi>C.</hi> might preſently aſſign the ſaid <hi>A.</hi> his Bond to <hi>D,</hi> and <hi>D.</hi> to <hi>E,</hi> &amp;c. And this would make all Bills, Bonds, and other Securities as good as ready Money; which will be of great uſe to the Subjects, and prevent the multiplicity of Suits that now happen; and thereby the ruines of many Families.</p>
               <p n="2">2ly. It will be of great advantage and ſecurity to the Gentry; for, if their Bills, Bonds, or other Securities, be aſſignable, perſons to whom they enter into ſuch Securities, though they want Money, will not be haſty to put their Securities in Suit, or compel them (as now they are forced to do) frequently to ſhift and alter Securities; which is chargeable and difficult; becauſe, then Bonds will be in the na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture of ready money, and in Trade be equally as good, when Aſſign<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments ſhall be Enacted to be irrevocable; and that Suits brought there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon by the Aſſignees, in their own Names, and to their own Uſes, ſhall not be diſcharged, but by delivering up the Securities themſelves, and that not without the conſent of the perſon to whom by Endorſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment on the back of ſuch Securities, it ſhall appear to have been laſt aſſigned: And to Enact that no perſon ſhall be Sued for a Book-Debt after three years, would be of excellent uſe both to Buyer and Sel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ler.</p>
               <p>For, frequently it hath happened, that Gentlemen who had taken up Goods upon Truſt, living remote in the Countrey, have afterwards ſent up Money, and paid for the ſame, but not ſeen the Book croſt; whereupon, many years after the Death of the Buyer and Seller, by the Executor of the Seller, the Buyer his Executor hath been Sued for the ſame, and the Plaintiffe hath recovered againſt him, meerly becauſe ſuch a Debt hath been found ſtanding in the Book, and the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livering
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:53444:31"/>of the Goods proved; and ſo a Verdict hath paſs'd againſt the Executor of the Debtor, becauſe he hath not been able to prove pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment for the ſame.</p>
               <p>How many, by letting Debts ſtand long in Shop-keepers Books, have when they came to accompt with them, found Entries made of Goods never bought by them, or of greater quantities than they had of ſuch Goods as they did buy.</p>
               <p>But if no Book-Debt ſhall be ſued for after three years ſtanding, it will oblige the Shop-keepers to come to accompt once in three years, and get Bill or Bond for their Moneys whilſt things are freſh in memo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, or elſe to ſue for the ſame, when if any thing be found unjuſt in their Books, the Creditor will be able, by his memory, to diſcover the ſame, and prevent payment thereof.</p>
               <p>Beſides, it will prevent Perjury and other foul practices.</p>
               <p n="3">3ly. This Act deſired would be of great advantage to the Nation in general; for when paſſed, all Bills, Bonds, and other good Securities will be <hi>Tanta-mount</hi> to ready Money, ſo that there will be 20000 <hi>l.</hi> or as good as 20000 <hi>l.</hi> in <hi>England,</hi> inſtead of every 1000 <hi>l.</hi> that now is paſſing in Trade; which muſt neceſſarily be a great advantage to the publick.</p>
               <p>This Courſe is practiſed in other Foreign Parts, and found of as great importance and benefit to Trade, as can be imagined.</p>
               <p>And for preventing the Miſchiefs ariſing to Traders by the Knave<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries of perſons pretending to be Bankrupts, and who break with de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign only to defraud their Creditors, ſome further and ſtricter Act muſt be made than hitherto there hath been; otherwiſe there will be no truſting any man, it being frequent for men of wicked and cheat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Principles, when they deſign to break, knowing themſelves to be perſons not ſuſpected to fail, but of a good Credit, to take up great Parcels of Goods, or Sums of Money of ſeveral other Tradeſmen; which ſo ſoon as they get into their hands, they diſpoſe unto Friends in truſt for them, and their Wives, and Children; which done, then they preſently do ſome Act whereby they become Bankrupts; as ſuch are proſecuted, Commiſſions taken out to declare them Bankrupts where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon they withdraw and abſcond themſelves in the Countrey, till they can get Releaſes from their Creditors, or compound for ſome ſmall matter, or otherwiſe they take the <hi>King's Bench,</hi> lie within the <hi>Rules,</hi> and frequently go abroad; and all that time have the Money they break for, going in Trade in other Names; and from ſuch their Truſtees, they receive the benefit thereof; wherewith they live high, whilſt their Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:53444:31"/>are undone by them; and if they cannot bring their Creditors to Compoſition, they will continue all their life-time in the <hi>King's-Bench,</hi> and the Creditors get nothing; ſo that their Creditors are fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quently brought to ſmall Compoſition: Which done, then theſe Bankrupts immediately appear in their Shops again richer than ever they were when firſt ſet up; and this with other honeſt mens Stocks, who with their Families are undone through the Loſſes ſuſtained by thoſe mens knaviſh breaking. And this Trick ſome men have plaid ſeveral times over; therefore it's fit for the future, if poſſible, to be prevented.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <head>XII.</head>
               <p>THe Twelfth Propoſal is, that the <hi>Newcaſtle</hi>-Trade for Coals be managed by Commiſſioners for the King, whereby the Subject may be ſupplied with Coals at eaſie Rates, and not be exacted upon, as they now are; and about 200000 <hi>l. per Annum</hi> be coming to the Crown; which would be a further help towards the payment of the publick Debts.</p>
               <p>I need not declare how the Subjects are abuſed in the price of Coals.</p>
               <p>How many poor have been ſtarved for want of Fewel, by reaſon of the horrid prices put upon them; eſpecially in time of War, either by the Merchant, or the Woodmonger, or between them both.</p>
               <p>That which I ſhall propoſe is,</p>
               <p>That the whole Trade be managed by Commiſſioners for the benefit of the publick.</p>
               <p>That thoſe Commiſſioners take care to ſupply all parts of His Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Dominions with Coals.</p>
               <p>That Coals be ſold all the year long at 22 <hi>s. per</hi> Chaldron; at which rate they may very well be afforded:</p>
               <p>For at <hi>Newcaſtle</hi> they buy them for about 7 <hi>s. per</hi> Chaldron. which rate they may very well be afforded:</p>
               <p>The <hi>Newcaſtle</hi>-Chaldron makes five <hi>London</hi>-Chaldrons.</p>
               <p>The Freight of each Chaldron is not above 6 <hi>s.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>The Duty to the City for each Chaldron is but 3 <hi>s.</hi>
               </p>
               <pb n="60" facs="tcp:53444:32"/>
               <p>Lighterage, Wharfage, and Cartage may coſt <hi>per</hi> Chaldron 4 <hi>s.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>I compute the higheſt Rates that can be imagined.</p>
               <p>And at theſe Rates, each <hi>Newcaſtle</hi>-Chaldron will lie the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners but in 20 <hi>s.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>If then three <hi>Newcaſtle</hi>-Chaldron computed at 3 <hi>l.</hi> make five <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi>-Chaldrons, and they be ſold for 5 <hi>l.</hi> 10 <hi>s.</hi> there is very nigh half in half gotten thereby: Conſidering then, how many hundred thouſand Chaldron of Coals are ſpent every year, and by a moderate computa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, it will appear that near 200000 <hi>l. per Annum</hi> advantage may ariſe hereby to the Publick, and the Subject alſo receive a great benefit by the ſame.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <head>XIII.</head>
               <p>THe laſt Propoſal is, That the Fiſhing-Trade may be ſet up and encouraged, all poor people ſet at work to make Fiſhing-Tackle, and be paid out of the yearly Rates laid upon the Subjects for maintain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the poor.</p>
               <p>This would be of vaſt advantage to the Publick.</p>
               <p>The Money yearly paid by the Subjects for the relief of the Poor, is nigh as much as an Aſſeſsment of 70000 <hi>l.</hi> a Month to the King.</p>
               <p>This is employed only to maintain idle Perſons, doth great hurt rather than good, makes a world of poor more than otherwiſe there would be, prevents Induſtry and Laboriouſneſs, Men and Women growing ſo idle and Proud, that they will not work, but lie upon the Pariſh wherein they dwell, for Maintenance, applying themſelves to nothing but Begging or Pilfering, and breeding up their Children ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cordingly, never putting them upon any thing that may render them uſeful in their Generations, or beneficial either to themſelves, or the Kingdom.</p>
               <p>But if inſtead of giving them Weekly Allowances for maintaining them in their Idleneſs, the Money collected were employed to ſet all of them that are able, at work to ſome kind of Employment or other, ſutable to their Capacities, it would be of infinite Uſe and Advantage to the Nation: There are none except Bedridden or Blind, but ſome Work or other may be found, that they may be capable of doing; which, if they would not ſet unto when appointed them, they ſhould have Correction, rather than any Encouragement, which now they
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:53444:32"/>have, by allowing them Weekly Maintenance. And thus, not only Men and Women would become uſeful and beneficial to the Kingdom, but their Children ſhould all of them be employed and ſet at work, to do ſomething or other that may keep them from Idleneſs; which be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coming habitual to them in their youth, they are ſeldom broke off whilſt they live.</p>
               <p>Induſtry and Labour ought to be countenanced and encouraged, and Magiſtrates and Gentry would do well to give Examples thereof to thoſe amongſt whom they live.</p>
               <p>If all the Poor now maintained in their Idleneſs, were ſet at work, and paid out of the Money raiſed as aforeſaid, thoſe that now have two Shillings, or three Shillings a Week, might by their Work earn ſo much; or ſuppoſe they could earn but one Shilling ſixpence a week, and nevertheleſs receive three Shillings, it is half in half ſaved; ſo that a Moyety of what now is collected from the people, might be ſpared to them, and yet the Poor be as well, or better maintained than now.</p>
               <p>But if Men, Women, and Children were ſet at work, few Families that now receive two or three Shillings a week, but in all probability, would and might earn four or five Shill. a week, help to Manufacture the Staple-Commodities of the Kingdom at cheap Rates, and thereby bring down the Wages of Handicrafts-men, which now are grown ſo high, that we have loſt the Trade of Foreign Conſumption, becauſe abroad Wool and Leather, and the Manufactures thereof, are ſold at lower Rates than we can afford ours at. This Miſchief of high Wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges to Handicrafts-men, is occaſioned by reaſon of the Idleneſs of ſo vaſt a number of people in <hi>England,</hi> as there are, ſo that thoſe that are Induſtrious, and will work, make men pay what they pleaſe for their Wages; but ſet the Poor at Work, and then theſe men will be forced to lower their Rates, whereby we ſhall quickly come to ſell as cheap as Foreigners do, and conſequently engroſs the Trade to our ſelves.</p>
               <p>There are many ways to ſet the Poor at work, both old and young.</p>
               <p>Women and Children, by Spinning of Linnen, Woollen, and Woolſted, Carding, Combing, Knitting, Working Plain-Work, or Points, Making Bone-Lace, or Thred-or Silk-Laces, Brede, and di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers other things.</p>
               <p>The Linnen-Trade, if well regulated, would employ ſome hundred thouſands of People; and if brought to perfection, might ſave vaſt Sums of Money, within the Kingdom, which now are ſent out for the ſame.</p>
               <p>The Woollen and Leathern-Manufactories would employ Multitudes
<pb n="92" facs="tcp:53444:33"/>of Men, and young youths, and vaſt quantities of Wooll might be manufactured and conſumed in <hi>England,</hi> more than now is, if all the Tapeſtry we now uſe, were made here, which is now imported from beyond the Seas. Alſo, if the Act for Burying in <hi>Flannel</hi> (as ridicu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lous as men make it) were put in Execution, ſeeing Flannel would be as good for that uſe, as Linnen, abundance of our Poor would be employed in making theſe things. And the Money now paid for theſe Foreign Manufactures, would be kept in <hi>England,</hi> and defray the Charge of the Manufacturing of them at home.</p>
               <p>It is not to be imagined how many thouſands of Men, Women, and Children the Fiſhing-Trade (which is that I principally aim at) would keep in employment. The making of the Nets, Sayls, Cordage, and other Materials for that uſe, the Building of Fiſhing-Veſſels, and the Catch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and Curing of the Fiſh, when catch'd, would find work for above two hundred thouſand People, and would encreaſe the number of Sea-men, Ship-wrights, and many Handicrafts-men: A great Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venue, if well managed, would thereby ariſe to the Publick; and the Fiſh taken would be as good to us, as ſo much Ready-Money; and be taken off beyond Seas, in Exchange for ſuch Goods as we neceſſarily want, and have from Foreign Parts, and now pay Ready Money for.</p>
               <p>To conclude, Were the things Propoſed as aforeſaid done, as deſired, Trade would be encouraged and encreaſed, the Proviſions and Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>factures of the Kingdom be in far greater quantities conſumed, both at home and abroad, the Price of Lands would be raiſed, Tenants be enabled to pay their Rents, the Kingdom would be greatly enriched, and in a few years the Publick Debts of the Kingdom might be diſcharged, without Impoſing any conſiderable Tax upon the People.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:53444:33"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
